Hi everybody, time to get started.
大家好，是时候开始了。
Okay. Um, so, so today what we're gonna talk about is a topic that's, um,
好的。嗯，所以今天我们要谈的是一个话题，嗯，
coreference resolution and I'll explain in just a minute what that is,
共同决议，我会在一分钟内解释这是什么，
um, but before getting on to that just a,
嗯，但在开始之前只是一个，
uh, couple of words on the announcements.
呃，关于公告的几句话。
Um, so the TAs are feverishly working on getting homework five grades worked out,
嗯，所以技术顾问正在疯狂地努力完成五年级的作业，
so we hope that we can deliver those to you, um,
所以我们希望我们可以把它们交给你，嗯，
tomorrow just in case you're anxious to know
明天以防万一你急于知道
them before you make your final decisions about things.
在你做出关于事情的最终决定之前。
And then, the other thing that you should be remembering
然后，你应该记住的另一件事
is that the milestone for the final project is this Tuesday.
是最终项目的里程碑是本周二。
Now, I will confess that even to me it seems like,
现在，我会承认即使对我来说，似乎，
"Boy, boy this milestone came around really quickly."
“男孩，男孩这个里程碑很快就来了。”
So you probably feel that doubly, I realize.
我意识到，你可能会感到倍加。
And so you know, I do apologize for that a little bit,
所以你知道，我为此道歉一点，
but you know, really our hope was that we could actually use this to be helpful,
但是你知道，我们真的希望我们能够真正使用它来提供帮助，
and to give you feedback on what you're doing and suggestions,
并就你正在做什么和建议给你反馈，
and it just really seemed like, well,
它真的好像，好吧，
the only chance in which we can kind of, um,
我们唯一有机会，嗯，
turn around giving more feedback on the projects, um,
转过身来对项目提供更多反馈，嗯，
before it goes into the final week of the quarter is if we can kind of get stuff,
在它进入季度的最后一周之前，如果我们可以得到东西，
um, Tuesday, and hope to be then,
嗯，星期二，希望到那时，
sort of turning it around again by the end of the week.
在本周结束时再次转过身来。
So the hope is to help you not to just,
所以希望是帮助你不要只是，
um, create obstacles and roadblocks in your life.
嗯，在你的生活中制造障碍和障碍。
Okay. So today what we're gonna do, um, is, uh,
好的。那么今天我们要做什么，嗯，呃，
learn more about a linguistic topic for a change and learn
了解有关变革和学习的语言主题的更多信息
some more stuff about what goes on in coreference resolution.
关于共同参照解决方案中发生了什么的更多内容。
So first of all, I'm gonna talk about the task,
首先，我要谈谈这项任务，
and then go on to some of the kinds of models that people,
然后继续一些人们的模型，
um, do for coreference resolution.
嗯，做共参考解决方案。
So first of all, what is it?
首先，它是什么？
Um, so the idea of coreference resolution is what we do, which we have a text,
嗯，因此我们所做的是共同解决的想法，我们有一个文本，
"Barack Obama nominated Hillary Rodham Clinton as his Secretary of State on
“巴拉克奥巴马提名希拉里罗德姆克林顿为他的国务卿
Monday," and this text like most texts are about entities,
星期一，“和大多数文本一样，这个文本是关于实体的，
where entities are commonly human beings,
实体通常是人类，
but they can be other things like God saw talking giraffes or whatever it is.
但他们可以是其他东西，如上帝看到长颈鹿或其他任何东西。
So it seems like we want to make,
所以看起来我们想做，
find where entities are mentioned.
找到提到实体的地方。
So my entities are mentioned,
所以提到了我的实体，
they're referred to as mentions.
他们被称为提及。
So things like Barack Obama and Secretary of State,
巴拉克奥巴马和国务卿等事情，
he, her, they are mentions of entities.
他，她，他们是实体的提及。
And then, when we talk about coreference resolution,
然后，当我们谈论共指消解时，
the task that we're wanting to do is say,
我们想要做的任务就是说，
which of these mentions refer to the same entity,
这些提及中的哪一个提到同一个实体，
the same real thing in the world.
世界上同样真实的东西。
So well, one entity that's mentioned in this text is Barack Obama,
那么，本文中提到的一个实体是巴拉克奥巴马，
and then he's referred to later in the text as his and he,
然后他在文中稍后提到他和他，
and so these three red noun phrases are all coreferent to each other.
所以这三个红色名词短语都是相互指责的。
And that then, refers to this real-world entity.
然后，指的是这个现实世界的实体。
Um, and then, we have these references Hillary Rodham Clinton,
嗯，然后，我们有这些参考希拉里罗德姆克林顿，
Secretary of State, her,
国务卿，她，
she, First Lady, they're all references to a different entity.
她，第一夫人，他们都是对不同实体的引用。
And so they all refer to this person.
所以他们都提到了这个人。
And so those are examples of our coreference.
所以这些是我们共同参与的例子。
Um, in a way this is triv- sort of seems obvious to a human being,
嗯，在某种程度上，这似乎对人类来说是显而易见的，
um, looking at things, um,
嗯，看着东西，嗯，
but it can actually be kind of tricky and hard.
但它实际上可能有点棘手和困难。
Um, so, um, I thought we could spend a few minutes doing
嗯，嗯，我想我们可以花几分钟做
interactive working out coreferents together so that you guys can,
交互式制定共同使用，以便你们可以，
um, think about it all for a few minutes.
嗯，想想几分钟。
Um, so here's part of a little story.
嗯，所以这是一个小故事的一部分。
Um, it's a story by Shruthi Rao called The Star.
嗯，这是Shruthi Rao所说的The Star的故事。
Um, now, I confess that since this is a CS class,
嗯，现在，我承认，因为这是一个CS类，
um, not a literature class,
嗯，不是文学课，
I did a little bit of, um,
我做了一点，嗯，
helpful editing of this text to make it shorter,
有用的编辑此文本，使其更短，
so I could fit more of,
所以我可以适应更多，
what was going on, um,
发生了什么事，嗯，
onto the page, um, but, um,
在页面上，嗯，但是，嗯，
everything that is a sort of a linguistic
一切都是语言学的
[inaudible] is something that comes from the original text.
[听不清]是来自原始文本的内容。
Okay. So, um, in this text,
好的。所以，嗯，在这篇文章中，
um, who is the first entity that's mentioned?
嗯，谁是第一个提到的实体？
Vanaja, okay.
Vanaja，好的。
Okay. So it's Vanaja.
好的。所以这是Vanaja。
Now, where, let's do it forward.
现在，在哪里，让我们前进吧。
Where else is Vanaja mentioned in this text?
Vanaja还有哪些内容在本文中提到过？
Her son, right?
她的儿子吧？
So this her not the son,
所以这不是儿子，
but this her is a reference of Vanaja, right?
但她这是Vanaja的参考，对吧？
Um, she resigned.
嗯，她辞职了。
Okay. After that?
好的。之后？
She bought.
她买了。
Okay. So there's another she.
好的。所以还有另一个她。
Was there another reference before that?
之前还有另一个参考吗？
Herself, right? So herself is also a reference to Vanaja.
她自己，对吗？所以她自己也是Vanaja的参考。
Um, okay. So then, it's again,
嗯，好的。那么，它又一次，
she made this, she, okay.
她做了这个，她，好吧。
So we've done Vanaja.
所以我们做了Vanaja。
Okay, that's a good start.
好的，这是一个好的开始。
Okay. So then, um, we've got Akhila.
好的。那么，嗯，我们有Akhila。
Okay. Um, where's Akhila next referred to?
好的。嗯，Akhila接下来提到的地方？
As Akhila. Okay, there we go.
作为阿希拉。好的，我们去吧。
Um, are there other references, um, to Akhila?
嗯，还有其他的参考，嗯，给Akhila？
Maybe not. Okay. What's the next entity that's mentioned?
也许不吧。好的。提到的下一个实体是什么？
Prajwal.
Prajwal。
Okay. So what other references are there to Prajwal?
好的。那么Prajwal有哪些其他参考资料？
They.
他们。
They? Okay. So here's a tricky one, right?
他们？好的。所以这是一个棘手的问题，对吗？
So this they, I mean,
所以他们，我的意思是，
who does that refer to?
这是指谁？
It occ- refers to Prajwal and Akash.
它指的是Prajwal和Akash。
Yeah, so this they refers both to Prajwal and this Akash.
是的，所以他们指的是Prajwal和这个Akash。
So that's, that's something that happens in human languages.
那就是，这是人类语言中发生的事情。
This is referred to as split antecedents,
这被称为分裂前因，
where you have one thing that they,
你有一件事，他们，
that's sort of referring to two distributed things that came before it.
这是指在它之前发生的两个分布式事物。
Um, so here's one of my first sad admissions of natural language processing technology.
嗯，所以这是我第一次对自然语言处理技术感到悲伤。
None of the NLP systems that we're gonna talk about later
我们之后将讨论的NLP系统都没有
today or in general that have been built deal with split antecedents.
今天或者一般来说，已经建立的处理分裂前因。
They automatically lose as soon as there's split antecedents.
一旦分裂前因，它们就会自动丢失。
Um, so that's a bit sad,
嗯，这有点难过，
um, but that's the state of technology.
嗯，但那是技术状态。
So it's something, um,
所以这是某种东西，嗯，
we could still work to improve,
我们仍然可以改进，
but okay there's this sort of they that's kind of half Prajwal. Um, okay.
但是没关系，他们就是那种半普拉瓦尔。嗯，好的。
So there's directly Prajwal here,
所以这里有直接的Prajwal，
but was there another place early in the text that Prajwal is effectively mentioned?
但在文本的早期还有另一个地方有效地提到了Prajwal吗？
Yeah. So Akhila's son is really another mention of Prajwal, right?
是啊。所以Akhila的儿子真的是另一个提到Prajwal，对吧？
Okay. Um, okay.
好的。嗯，好的。
Um, any other mentions of Prajwal? Maybe not.
嗯，其他任何提到的Prajwal？也许不吧。
Okay. Then we go on.
好的。然后我们继续。
Okay. Who's the next entity?
好的。谁是下一个实体？
Akash. So we have Akash here,
阿卡什。所以我们这里有阿卡什，
and that then again,
那又一次，
we have that her son referring to Akash.
我们有她的儿子提到阿卡什。
Um, and here was Akash.
嗯，这里是阿卡什。
Okay. What other, what other mentions of Akash are there?
好的。还有什么，还有其他提到的阿卡什？
Okay so there's another Akash here, um, fourth him.
好的，这里还有另一个阿卡什，嗯，第四个他。
Okay. Uh, there's another Akash.
好的。呃，还有另一个阿卡什。
Okay, um, but, so, um, here.
好的，嗯，但是，嗯，这里。
Okay. So are the obvious Akash's.
好的。明显的阿卡什也是如此。
There's sort of a tricky case here which
这里有一个棘手的案例
you could wonder what the right treatment of this, right?
你可能想知道对这个有什么正确的对待，对吧？
You know, it's sort of says Akash was to be a tree, all right.
你知道，有点像阿卡什是一棵树，好吧。
So in some sense the tree is Akash.
所以在某种意义上，树是阿卡什。
Um, so really in terms of reference in this story,
嗯，这个故事的参考真的如此，
the reference of the tree is the same as Akash.
树的引用与Akash相同。
And you could think, um,
你可以想，嗯，
that means you should treat the instances of,
这意味着你应该对待实例，
um, the tree, the,
嗯，树，the，
the instances here of the tree,
树的实例，
and later on when the nicest tree right that really,
后来当最好的树真的，
that's sort of this Akash as well.
这也是阿卡什的一种。
That doesn't quite feel right,
那感觉不对，
but this is something that comes up in coreference, right?
但这是在共识中出现的，对吧？
So here we have a sort of a predictive construction um,
所以这里我们有一种预测结构，
with, you know, B.
有，你知道，B.
And when you set,
当你设置，
when you have sentences such as like, um, you know,
当你有像呃这样的句子时，你知道，
my child is the smartest kid in the class or something like that, in some sense,
在某种意义上，我的孩子是班上最聪明的孩子或类似的东西，
you're sort of saying that the smartest kid in
你是说那个最聪明的孩子
the class has the same reference as my child.
该班与我的孩子有相同的参考。
And some systems count links over that kind of predication,
有些系统会计算这种预测的链接，
and say that is coreference whereas
并说这是共同参与
other ones don't and think that that's not quite reasonable.
其他人不这样做，并认为这不太合理。
So different things go on.
所以不同的事情继续下去。
Okay. So, um, those,
好的。所以，嗯，那些，
those are fair number of entities.
这些是相当数量的实体。
I mean, so there are obviously lots of other things that are mentioned,
我的意思是，所以很明显还有很多其他的东西，
um that sort of, um, right?
那是那种，对吧？
So there's the local park, right,
所以有当地的公园，对，
that's a mention of some entity.
这是一个实体的提及。
Um, there's, um, the school, um right?
嗯，那是，嗯，学校，对吗？
So there's this school here and so that the school is coreferent with pre,
所以这里有这所学校，所以学校与pre，
the preschool right here, right?
幼儿园就在这里，对吗？
Um, and then there's,
嗯，然后就是，
um, again this sort of tricky one,
嗯，再次这种棘手的，
of how to treat the naughty child Lord Krishna because,
如何对待顽皮的孩子克里希纳勋爵，因为，
you know, in some sense Prajwal is representing that.
你知道，在某种意义上，Prajwal代表了这一点。
And then there are lots of other entities that are mentioned, right?
然后提到了很多其他实体，对吧？
There's a t-shirt, and there's trousers,
有一件T恤，还有裤子，
um, and, um, things like that.
嗯，嗯，这样的事情。
Another tricky thing that turns up here when you get later on into
当你稍后进入时，另一个棘手的事情就会出现在这里
the story is you can have entities that have parts.
故事是你可以拥有有部分的实体。
So we not only have a tree,
所以我们不仅有一棵树，
but that tree then has a lot of parts, right?
但那棵树有很多部分，对吧？
So the tree has a trunk,
所以树有一个树干，
and the tree has foliage,
树上有树叶，
um, and things like that.
嗯，等等。
And there are these red balls that are representing fruits, right?
这些红球代表水果，对吧？
So there's a lot of stuff that's somehow connected together and somehow separate.
所以有很多东西以某种方式连接在一起，并以某种方式分开。
And that sort of, that doesn't fit terribly well with the kind of models we
而那种，与我们的那种模型不太匹配
use with coreference either because really we make our coreference,
与coreference一起使用要么是因为我们真正做了我们的共同参与，
um, reference models basically out of this notion of entities.
嗯，参考模型基本上是出于这种实体的概念。
Um, but somehow there's this complexity that,
嗯，但不知何故有这种复杂性，
you know, human beings have parts too, right?
你知道，人类也有部分，对吧？
We have hands and faces,
我们有手和脸，
and we can't say, oh, that's a separate entity,
我们不能说，哦，那是一个单独的实体，
but they're somehow in, um, involved with the other entity.
但他们在某种程度上与另一个实体有关。
Okay. Um, hope that's sort of useful to give some idea.
好的。嗯，希望能给出一些想法是有用的。
Why is coreference resolution useful?
为什么共参考分辨率有用？
Um, so there are all kinds of things that we'd like to do well
嗯，所以我们都想做好各种各样的事情
in natural language processing that you really can't do well unless,
在自然语言处理中你真的不能做得好，除非，
uh, you know how to do coreference resolution.
呃，你知道如何做共识解析。
So anything that we want to do in terms of question-answering, summarization,
所以我们想要做的任何问题，总结，
extracting facts from texts or anything like that,
从文本或类似的东西中提取事实，
there are places we are gonna fail unless we can do coreference resolution.
除非我们能够做出共识解决方案，否则我们会失败的地方。
Because if we're reading a piece of text,
因为如果我们正在阅读一段文字，
and it says he was born in 1961, um,
它说它出生于1961年，嗯，
we can get a fact out or answer a question,
我们可以得出一个事实或回答一个问题，
if we can work out who he was,
如果我们能弄清楚他是谁，
but we probably can't otherwise.
但我们可能不会这样。
Um, there are, there's sort of another place that where
嗯，还有，那里有另一个地方
this is very useful is in machine translation,
这在机器翻译中非常有用，
so that lots of languages drop pronouns.
这样许多语言都会掉落代词。
So you don't have to give explicit pronouns,
所以你不必给出明确的代词，
but you need to be able to work out how to fill them in.
但你需要能够弄清楚如何填写它们。
And this is making coreference decisions about,
这是关于做出共识的决定，
um, arguments of verbs.
嗯，动词的论点。
And so here are a couple of examples,
所以这里有几个例子，
um, that, um, covering from Spanish to English.
嗯，那，嗯，从西班牙语到英语。
So in Spanish, you can freely drop the subjects of verbs and in these sentences,
所以在西班牙语中，你可以自由地删除动词的主语，并在这些句子中，
in the because clause,
在因子句中，
there's no overt subject.
没有明显的主题。
And so he gets Alicia likes Juan because he's smart.
所以他让Alicia喜欢Juan，因为他很聪明。
And so Google Translate is stuck in a he and that is right.
所以谷歌翻译陷入困境，这是正确的。
And to stick in that he,
并坚持他，
it's implicitly making a coreference decision and saying, "Okay well,
它暗中做出了一个共识决定并说：“好吧，
the subject of this, um,
这个主题，嗯，
adjective smart should be Juan who's male,
形容词聪明应该是胡安谁的男性，
and therefore, I should say he."
因此，我应该说他。“
But, you know, the reality is Google Translate knows
但是，你知道，现实是谷歌翻译知道
nothing about coreference and making these coreference decisions.
没有关于共同参与和做出这些共同决策的决定。
And as has been um,
就像那样，
covered quite a bit in the media now and I think came up earlier in an earlier class,
现在媒体报道了很多，我想早些时候在早期的课程中出现了，
that, um, Google Translate mainly just defaults to male default.
那，嗯，谷歌翻译主要是默认为男性默认。
Um, so if you sort of swap- sweep it, uh,
嗯，如果你换掉它，呃，
if you flip it around and say,
如果你翻转并说，
Juan likes Alicia, it also says because he's smart.
胡安喜欢艾丽西亚，也说因为他很聪明。
Uh, whereas probably it should be because she's smart in that case.
呃，可能应该是因为她在那种情况下很聪明。
And indeed you notice the bad effects of that everywhere.
事实上，你注意到了各地的不良影响。
So many languages, um, Turkish, Indonesian, um,
这么多语言，嗯，土耳其语，印度尼西亚语，嗯，
don't actually have gender,
实际上没有性别，
so that they're much less sexist languages than English,
这样他们的性别语言比英语少得多，
French or Germany is.
法国人或德国人。
But what happens, um,
但是会发生什么，嗯，
when you then translate where you just have
当你然后翻译你所拥有的
a generic pronoun that means third person pronoun, um,
一个通用代词，意思是第三人称代词，嗯，
that Google Translate is essentially using its language model,
谷歌翻译基本上使用其语言模型，
which means that reconstructs, um,
这意味着重建，嗯，
the worst of stereotypes of she is a cook,
最糟糕的刻板印象是她是一名厨师，
and he is an engineer, he is a doctor.
他是一名工程师，他是一名医生。
And well, in a connected piece of this course,
好吧，在本课程的相关部分中，
if you'd like Google Translate to be able to do better than that,
如果你想谷歌翻译能够做得更好，
well again, what would be required is that you could actually do
再说一遍，需要的是你实际可以做到的
coreference resolution and track along the actors in the text as you go along.
随时随地解决和跟踪文本中的演员。
Um, one final example we haven't really talked about yet,
嗯，我们还没有真正谈过的最后一个例子，
but we'll get back to soon now because the class is almost over
但我们现在很快就会回来，因为课程已经快结束了
is doing things with dialogue agents or chat systems.
正在与对话代理或聊天系统做事。
That, as soon as you are going to do anything more than a single turn,
那，只要你打算做一个以上的转弯，
um, dialog, that you need to start dealing with reference.
对话框，你需要开始处理参考。
So if you've got something like, um,
所以，如果你有类似的东西，嗯，
booked tickets to see James Bond,
预订门票，看詹姆斯邦德，
um, then you want to say something like,
嗯，那你想说点什么，
"Spectre is playing near you at 2:00 and 3:00 today.
“幽灵今天凌晨2点到3点在你附近玩耍。
How many tickets would you like?"
你想要多少张票？”
Um, two tickets for the showing at three.
嗯，三张票的两张票。
That as shown in the color,
如图所示，
there are various kinds of reference going on here where things have related reference,
这里有各种各样的参考，其中有相关的参考，
but it's kind of complicated here.
但这里有点复杂。
And this is something that we'll come back to in a moment.
这是我们马上回过头来的。
So James Bond and Spectre aren't obviously the same thing,
所以James Bond和Spectre显然不是一回事，
but in a context like, um, booking movies,
但在这样的情况下，嗯，预订电影，
they are the same thing because one is the name of a character in a movie series,
它们是同一个东西，因为一个是电影系列中角色的名字，
and the other is the name of a movie that's currently showing that belongs to that,
另一个是当前显示属于那个的电影的名称，
so that they're sort of associated, um,
所以他们有点联系，嗯，
in a sort of subtle way that isn't exact identity,
以某种微妙的方式，不是确切的身份，
but is relevant to a lot of the things that we want to do.
但与我们想要做的很多事情有关。
I'll come back to that in a little bit when we
我们稍后会回到那一点
talk a bit more about the linguistics of this.
再谈谈这个语言学。
Okay. So if we want to do the task of coreference resolution,
好的。所以，如果我们想完成共参考解决的任务，
there are essentially two steps.
基本上有两个步骤。
So the first step is gee, we want to work out
所以第一步是gee，我们想要解决
what mentions there are in the text that we should be doing something with.
文中提到我们应该做些什么。
And this one is effectively pretty easy,
这个很容易，
but I'll have just a few slides on that immediately.
但我马上就会有几张幻灯片。
And then what the bulk of the class is gonna be on is,
然后，课程的大部分内容是，
um, working out coreference between mentions.
嗯，在提及之间制定共识。
And if you think about this,
如果你考虑这个，
coreference is essentially a clustering task.
coreference本质上是一个集群任务。
Because if you do the first task,
因为如果你做第一个任务，
you have a set of mentions and then you want to be saying well,
你有一套提及，然后你想说得好，
how can I group these into clusters that have the same reference?
如何将这些组合成具有相同引用的簇？
And so that's what we're going to look more at doing.
这就是我们将要做的更多。
So quickly on mention detection.
如此迅速提及检测。
So, um, for mention,
那么，嗯，提一下，
we wanna find all the spans that are candidates for,
我们想要找到所有候选的跨度，
um, referring to some entity.
嗯，指某个实体。
And the answer to what these, um,
这些的答案，嗯，
candidates are is basically they're all the noun phrases in the text.
候选人基本上都是文本中的所有名词短语。
And so normally people think of there being three types of mentions that we identify.
因此，通常人们会想到我们确定有三种类型的提及。
There are pronouns, I,
有代词，我，
you, he, she, it,
你，他，她，它，
etc., that are, um,
等等，嗯，
referring to different entities.
指的是不同的实体。
They're explicit names of people like that was
他们是这样的人的明确名字
that Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton examples.
巴拉克奥巴马和希拉里克林顿的例子。
And then many of the tricky examples,
然后是许多棘手的例子，
and then when we have common noun phrases
然后当我们有共同的名词短语
like a dog or the big fluffy cat stuck in the tree.
像一只狗或被困在树上的大毛茸茸的猫。
That the big fluffy cat stuck in the tree is a mention.
那个大蓬松的猫卡在树上是一个提及。
Um, it's actually a complex mention because it
嗯，这实际上是一个复杂的提及，因为它
also has embedded inside it other mentions.
其他提到也嵌入其中。
Um, so the tree is also a mention.
嗯，树也是一提。
Okay. So how can we detect mentions?
好的。那么我们怎样才能发现提及？
Well, one answer is to say,
嗯，一个答案就是说，
well we've looked at, um,
好吧，我们看了，嗯，
various other NLP systems on and off.
各种其他NLP系统开启和关闭。
And we can just use those NLP systems as preprocessing systems to find mentions.
我们可以使用这些NLP系统作为预处理系统来查找提及。
So for pronouns, they're part of speech taggers that say what's a noun,
所以对于代词而言，它们是言语标记的一部分，它们说什么是名词，
or a verb, or a pronoun,
或动词或代名词
and so we can run those and find all the pronouns and we're done.
所以我们可以运行那些并找到所有的代词，我们就完成了。
From- for, um, the names of things like Barack Obama.
从那以后，嗯，像巴拉克奥巴马这样的东西的名字。
We've talked a couple of times about named entity recognizers,
我们已经谈了几次关于命名实体识别器的事情，
so we can run those and find all the named entities.
所以我们可以运行它们并找到所有命名的实体。
Um, then for common noun phrases,
嗯，然后是普通名词短语，
that's sort of where we need parsers to find
这就是我们需要解析器找到的地方
the structure of the sentence and find where the noun phrases are.
句子的结构，并找到名词短语的位置。
And we have talked about dependency parsers and well,
我们已经讨论过依赖解析器了，
one choice is you can use a dependency parser to find the sort of nominal arguments,
一个选择是你可以使用依赖解析器来找到名义参数的类型，
and work with them.
并与他们合作。
That's sort of actually a little bit subtler than just sort of wanting to pick
这有点像一些想要挑选的东西
out spans that refer to common noun phrases.
指出常用名词短语的跨度。
So the other notion of parsing which we come back to,
所以解析我们回到的另一个概念，
um, next week is constituency parsing.
嗯，下周是选区解析。
In some sense, constituency parsers are
在某种意义上，选区解析器是
the simplest way to find mentions for this process.
查找此过程的最简单方法。
Um, most of it seems and is easy,
嗯，大部分看似简单，
um, there are sort of tricky cases as to what counts as a mention or not.
嗯，有一些棘手的案例，无论是否提及。
So, um, if it's kind of it is sunny,
所以，嗯，如果有点阳光，
I mean, is it a mention of something?
我的意思是，它提到了什么吗？
It's sort of seems like it's not really,
这有点像是不是真的，
it's just it seems like it's an it that you stick at the start of the sentence,
只是它似乎是你坚持在句子的开头，
um, that doesn't mean anything.
嗯，这并不意味着什么。
So that's maybe not a mention.
所以这可能不是一个提及。
Um, every student.
嗯，每个学生。
Is every student a mention?
每个学生都被提及吗？
I mean, it's certainly, at best it's some kind of collective,
我的意思是，这当然是充其量的集体，
um, but it's not sort of a very clear concrete reference, um.
嗯，但这不是一个非常明确的具体参考，嗯。
That goes further, if I sort of use different quantifiers,
更进一步，如果我使用不同的量词，
so if it was like, every and no are called quantifiers.
所以，如果是这样的话，每一个都不称为量词。
I mean no student definitely doesn't have reference,
我的意思是没有学生肯定没有参考，
because it's not pointing at anything, right?
因为它没有指向任何东西，对吗？
It's asserting a claim of nonexistence.
它声称不存在。
So that there's definitely, um,
所以，肯定，嗯，
no- it isn't a mention of anything.
不，它没有任何提及。
Um, yeah, the best donut in the world.
嗯，是的，世界上最好的甜甜圈。
Um, does that have reference?
嗯，那有参考吗？
Um, that's unclear.
嗯，那还不清楚。
This is the kind of thing that actual philosophers of language debate over, right?
这是语言辩论的实际哲学家的事情，对吧？
So if there was agreement on what the best donut in the world is,
因此，如果就世界上最好的甜甜圈达成一致意见，
then maybe it has reference, um,
也许它有参考，嗯，
but I can say sentences like,
但我可以说句话，
I'm searching everywhere to find the best donut in the world.
我到处寻找世界上最好的甜甜圈。
And then in that sentence,
然后在那句话中，
it doesn't have any reference, right?
它没有任何参考，对吧？
It's sort of an intentional description of what I'm hoping to find,
这是对我希望找到的有意描述，
that there's no concrete thing it refers to.
它指的是没有具体的东西。
Um, things like quantities, 100 miles.
嗯，数量之类的东西，100英里。
That sort of behaves like a noun phrase,
那种行为就像一个名词短语，
but it is in- it's sort of really a quantity that doesn't really have reference.
但它实际上是一个真正没有参考的数量。
Um, and so then there's the question of how can you deal with this stuff?
嗯，那么问题是你如何处理这些东西？
Um, well, um, our tool whenever we want to deal with stuff,
嗯，嗯，嗯，我们的工具，只要我们想要处理的东西，
is we train classifiers,
我们训练分类器，
as in they pick out things that are mentioned and things that aren't.
就像他们挑选出提到的东西和不提到的东西一样。
And so that's something that you could do is write a classifier that filters out,
所以你可以做的就是写一个过滤掉的分类器，
um, these spurious things that you want to say aren't really mentions.
嗯，你想说的这些虚假的东西并不是真正提到的。
And people absolutely have done that.
人们绝对做到了。
But commonly actually people skip that step,
但通常人们会跳过这一步，
and you just sort of instead have your mention detector find all candidate mentions.
而你只是让你的提及探测器找到所有候选人提及。
Because it turns out that that tends to work pretty well.
因为事实证明它往往效果很好。
Because after we found all of our mentions, um,
因为我们发现了所有的提及之后，嗯，
we're then going to be doing this clustering process to find coreferent mentions.
然后我们将进行这种聚类过程以找到相关的提及。
And if there are just a few stray mentions like
如果只有一些流浪提及像
no student and we don't cluster them wrongly with anything else,
没有学生，我们不会错误地将他们与其他任何东西聚集在一起，
it kind of doesn't do any harm because we are mainly involved in this clustering process.
它有点不会造成任何伤害，因为我们主要参与这个聚类过程。
Okay. Um, something you might be wondering is,
好的。嗯，你可能想知道的是，
well I've sort of implied now,
我现在有点暗示，
we have a pipeline.
我们有一条管道。
I'm saying we're going to run a part of speech tagger,
我说我们要运行一个词性标记器，
and we're going to run a named entity recognizer,
我们要运行一个命名实体识别器，
and we're going to run a parser.
我们要运行一个解析器。
And we're going to run a, um,
我们要跑一个，嗯，
a named mention detector.
一个名为提及探测器。
And then eventually, we're going to run this coref clustering system,
最后，我们将运行这个coref集群系统，
so we have a sort of a five-step pipeline.
所以我们有一个五步管道。
Um, is that the only way you can do, um, coreference resolution?
嗯，这是你可以做的唯一方法，嗯，共识解决方案？
And the traditional answer was yup,
而传统的答案是，
that's the way you did coreference resolution.
这就是你进行共识解析的方式。
That essentially, all systems for coreference resolution,
基本上，所有用于共同参考解决的系统，
until approximately 2016 where a pipeline that went through about those stages.
直到大约2016年，管道经历了这些阶段。
Um, but just recently and I will dico- cover one such system,
嗯，但就在最近，我将覆盖一个这样的系统，
um, later in the class, um,
嗯，后来在课堂上，嗯，
that people in the neural world have started doing what's been
神经世界的人们已经开始做了什么
effective in a lot of places in the neural network world of saying,
在神经网络世界的许多地方有效说，
can we just build an end-to-end coreference system
我们可以建立一个端到端的共同参与系统吗？
that starts with just plain text of a paragraph,
从段落的纯文本开始，
and feeds out coreference clusters without there being any intervening pipeline steps?
并且在没有任何干预管道步骤的情况下输出共享集群？
And I'll show you a bit more about how that works.
我会告诉你更多关于它是如何工作的。
Um, but before we get into systems,
嗯，但在我们进入系统之前，
I just wanted to say a little bit more about the linguistics of coreference.
我只想更多地谈谈共识的语言学。
Um, there's actually quite a lot of interesting stuff here,
嗯，这里有很多有趣的东西，
and to a fair degree,
在相当程度上，
it's not actually stuff that's been thought about
它实际上并不是人们所想的
very much by people who build NLP systems, right?
很多人建立NLP系统，对吧？
I already mentioned, um,
我已经提过了，嗯，
from the Shruthi Rao story, um,
来自Shruthi Rao的故事，嗯，
the example of split antecedents, right?
拆分前因的例子，对吧？
That that's just a clear linguistic phenomenon that happens,
这只是一个明显的语言现象，
and it's not even incredibly rare, right?
它甚至不是非常罕见，对吧？
Um, that, you know, um,
嗯，那个，你知道，嗯，
people build these simple machine learning models that just can't deal with that.
人们构建了这些简单的机器学习模型，但却无法解决这个问题。
And there's really quite a bit more structure
而且结构确实相当多
to what happens in the linguistics of coreference,
在共同语言学中发生的事情，
it isn't really being exploited in most of the systems people bui- build.
在人们建立的大多数系统中，它并没有真正被利用。
So I just wanted to show people a bit more of that.
所以我只是想向人们展示一点。
And essentially, to sort of understanding, um,
基本上，为了理解，嗯，
more about how people see things linguistically,
更多关于人们如何在语言上看待事物，
there are two concepts that are related and commonly confused,
有两个相关且常常混淆的概念，
that are really different.
真的不一样。
So one is coreference.
所以一个是共同参与。
So we say that things are coreferent when there are
所以我们说事情是有目共睹的
two mentions and they refer to the same entity in the world.
两个提及，他们指的是世界上的同一个实体。
So if it's sort of,
所以，如果它是那种，
um, Donald Trump and the current president, right?
嗯，唐纳德特朗普和现任总统，对吧？
They're two mentions and they refer to the same person in the world.
他们是两个提及，他们指的是世界上的同一个人。
And so that is a relationship of coreference.
这就是共同参与的关系。
Um, and that's then contrasted, um, with anaphora.
嗯，然后那个与anaphora对比了。
And so the idea of anaphora is some terms in text don't have independent reference,
所以回指的想法是文中的一些术语没有独立的参考，
and you work out their reference by relating them back to another thing in the text.
并通过将它们与文本中的另一个内容联系起来来确定它们的参考。
So if we have the sentence,
所以，如果我们有句子，
Barack Obama said he would sign the bill.
巴拉克奥巴马表示他将签署该法案。
He is an anaphor.
他是一个照应者。
And if I just say, he,
如果我只是说，他，
what does he refer to in the abstract?
他在摘要中提到了什么？
Well, you know, apart from saying something male, right?
嗯，你知道，除了说一些男性，对吧？
You've got no idea, right?
你不知道，对吧？
Because you can't work out what he means just by knowing he.
因为只要知道他就无法弄清楚他的意思。
You have to be looking at a text and interpreting it relative to the text.
您必须查看文本并相对于文本进行解释。
And then if you're interpreting it,
如果你在解释它，
um, relative to the text,
嗯，相对于文字，
you're then in this situation of,
你是在这种情况下，
okay I see, this refers back to Barack Obama.
好吧，我知道，这可以追溯到巴拉克奥巴马。
So he is another mention of Barack Obama,
所以他又提到了巴拉克奥巴马，
then- and this then is this concept of anaphora.
然后 - 这就是这个回指的概念。
So the picture we have is sort of like this,
所以我们的图片有点像这样，
that you can either have these independent mentions,
你可以有这些独立的提及，
which do refer, um,
这是指，嗯，
to the same thing in the world.
在世界上同样的事情。
They're coreferent.
他们是共同的。
But in many cases,
但在很多情况下，
such as when they're full mentions like President Obama,
比如他们像奥巴马总统那样全面提到，
versus Barack Obama, they don't have any textual relationship.
与巴拉克奥巴马相比，他们没有任何文字关系。
It's just they happen to refer to the same thing in the world.
只是他们恰好引用了世界上同样的事情。
And that then contrast with cases like Barack Obama said he would do something,
然后，与巴拉克奥巴马这样的案件形成对比，他说他会做点什么，
where the he has a textual relationship back to Barack Obama.
他与巴拉克奥巴马有文本关系。
And that's an example of anaphora.
这是回指的一个例子。
Um, this might up until now feel like an almost meaningless distinction.
嗯，这可能到现在为止几乎是毫无意义的区别。
But something that maybe gives you more of a sense that there's something useful here is,
但是有些东西可能会让你更加意识到这里有一些有用的东西，
um, these textual relationships exist even when there isn't coreference.
嗯，即使没有共同参与，这些文本关系也存在。
So we sort of mentioned before,
所以我们之前提到过，
these cases like no dancer, right?
这些情况就像没有舞者一样吧？
So no dancer doesn't have reference, right?
所以没有舞者没有参考，对吧？
It refers to nothing.
它什么都没说。
Um, but if you have a sentence like,
嗯，但如果你有句话，
"no dancer twisted her knee," well we have an anaphor here.
“没有舞者扭曲她的膝盖，”我们在这里有一个照应。
And that anaphor is referring back to "no
那个照应是指“不
dancer" despite the fact that "no dancer" doesn't have reference.
舞者“尽管”没有舞者“没有参考。
So we can still have the anaphoric textual relationship.
所以我们仍然可以有照应的文本关系。
And indeed, you know,
事实上，你知道，
her knee is then a part of her.
她的膝盖是她的一部分。
And so these are the sort of part relationships again.
所以这些又是那种部分关系。
But her knee, in a sense that I'll just come back to,
但她的膝盖，在某种意义上我会回来，
is also an anaphor which is interpreted with respect, um, to the dancer.
也是一个对舞者有尊重的解释。
So we have two anaphoric relationships here,
所以我们这里有两个照应关系，
even though we have no reference.
即使我们没有参考。
There's another interesting case of
还有一个有趣的案例
anaphoric relationships which aren't the same as reference,
与照参考不同的照应关系，
which is you could have looser forms of anaphoric relationships.
你可以拥有更宽松的照应关系形式。
So you get lots of sentences like this.
所以你会得到很多像这样的句子。
"We went to see a concert last night,
“昨晚我们去看了一场音乐会，
the tickets were really expensive."
门票很贵。“
So we have this mentioned here of the tickets.
所以我们在这里提到了门票。
Um, but really to interpret the tickets,
嗯，但真的要解释门票，
we have to interpret them with respect to this,
我们必须解释它们，
um, mention back here,
嗯，请回到这里，
a concept, because really what this is saying,
一个概念，因为这真的是这样说的，
the tickets for the concert were really expensive.
音乐会的门票非常昂贵。
So this is also referred to as an anaphoric relationship,
所以这也被称为照应关系，
where the meaning of the tickets has to be interpreted
必须解释门票的含义
textually based on another, um, noun phrase.
文本地基于另一个，嗯，名词短语。
But it's not a coreference relationship that
但它不是一种共同参与关系
the concert and the tickets are clearly two different entities.
音乐会和门票显然是两个不同的实体。
So these kinda looser cases are referred to as bridging anaphora,
所以这些宽松的案件被称为桥接回指，
because you sort of have to supply for yourself the bridge,
因为你有点必须为自己供应桥梁，
the relation that connects together the antecedent and the anaphor.
将先行者和回忆者联系在一起的关系。
Okay. So that's how- we then have these pictures,
好的。这就是我们如何拥有这些图片，
that we have this sort of not in- not complete crossovers
我们有这种并非完全交叉
between coreference and anaphora that we've sort of talked about.
在我们讨论过的共识和回指之间。
Um, I have one other note on anaphora. Um,
嗯，我还有另外一个关于回指的说明。嗯，
Who- has anyone here ever done any Ancient Greek?
谁 - 这里有人做过任何古希腊人吗？
Any Ancient Greek? [LAUGHTER] Yes.
任何古希腊人？ [大笑]是的。
Okay. Um, so, um,
好的。嗯，恩，嗯，
from- from the origins of the words anaphora,
来自 - 回指的起源，
anaphora is meant to be that you're finding your textual reference before you.
回指是指你在找到自己的文本参考之前。
Um, and so there's actually a- a complementary, um,
嗯，所以实际上是一个互补的，嗯，
term of art which is referred to as
被称为的艺术术语
cataphora where you're finding your reference after you.
cataphora你在哪里找到你的参考。
Um, so here is a beautiful example of cataphora.
嗯，所以这里是cataphora的一个美丽的例子。
So this is from Oscar Wilde's,
所以这是来自奥斯卡王尔德的，
The Picture of Dorian Gray.
多利安格雷的图片。
"From the corner of the divan of Persian saddle-bags on which he was lying,
“从他撒谎的波斯马鞍袋的角落里，
smoking, as was his custom,
吸烟，就像他的风俗一样，
innumerable cigarettes, Lord Henry Wotton could just catch
无数的香烟，亨利沃顿勋爵可以抓住
the gleam of the honey-sweet and honey-colored blossoms of a laburnum."
金莲花的蜂蜜甜蜜和蜂蜜色的花朵。“
Um, right. So here we have this, um, mentioned,
嗯，对。所以在这里，我们有这个，嗯，提到，
Lord Henry Wotton and there are two anaphors,
亨利沃顿勋爵和两个有点，
um, that refer to Lord Henry Wotton.
嗯，指亨利沃顿勋爵。
Um, he and his,
嗯，他和他的，
and that they both come before,
并且他们都来过，
um, Lord Henry Wotton.
嗯，亨利沃顿勋爵。
And so these are referred to, um,
所以这些都是指的，嗯，
as instances of cataphora among a certain kind of classical scholar.
作为某种古典学者中的cataphora的例子。
Um, and in case you don't know what a laburnum is,
嗯，如果你不知道什么是金链花，
um, this is a laburnum.
嗯，这是一个金链花。
[LAUGHTER] Right. But, yeah,
[大笑]对。但是，是的，
so thi- this is cataphora.
所以这是cataphora。
Now- now there are two sad things to say.
现在 - 现在有两件令人伤心的事情要说。
Um, the first sad thing is in modern linguistics,
嗯，第一件令人伤心的事是现代语言学，
the term cataphora is completely disused.
cataphora一词完全被废弃了。
And we mean- we just used the word um, anaphors everywhere as meaning
我们的意思是 - 我们只是用um这个词，无处不在的意思
a word that gets referenced from some other mention in
从其他一些提及引用的词
the text and it doesn't matter what side it's on.
文本和它在哪一方并不重要。
Um, so, um, that we go downhill one stage to
嗯，所以，嗯，我们走下坡去一个阶段
linguistics but then we get to NLP and we go downhill a second stage.
语言学然后我们到达NLP，我们走下坡路第二阶段。
Because what you'll see is that in general,
因为你会看到的是一般的，
the systems that people are building for,
人们正在建设的系统，
um, reference resolution, they don't make any distinction of direction at all.
嗯，参考分辨率，他们根本没有任何方向的区别。
That once you find a mention,
一旦你找到提及，
you're always looking backwards for its reference.
你总是在寻找它的参考。
Um, and you've got no idea that,
嗯，你不知道，
well, maybe sometimes you could look forwards.
好吧，也许有时候你可以向前看。
So effectively, what it means,
如此有效，意味着什么，
that the systems end up doing is saying,
系统最终做的是说，
well, there's a he here,
好吧，他在这里，
there are various other things, there's a his, etc.,
还有其他各种各样的东西，还有他的等等，
and you'll eventually get to Lord Henry Wotton and you'll be able to
你最终会得到亨利沃顿勋爵，你将能够
be trying to find its reference by looking backwards,
试图通过向后看，找到它的参考，
even though that's sort of ill-formed from any kind of linguistic sense
尽管从任何一种语言意义上来说都是不正确的
whereas really he and his that should have been looking for their reference forward.
真的，他和他应该一直在寻找他们的参考。
Okay. Um, is everyone good up to there, any questions?
好的。嗯，大家都很擅长，有什么问题吗？
Okay. We'll move ahead and, um,
好的。我们会继续前进，嗯，
try and move on to kinds of coreference, um, models.
尝试继续使用各种共识，嗯，模型。
So I wanted to, um, tell you, um,
所以我想，嗯，告诉你，嗯，
as much as I can and I have 45 minutes, um,
尽我所能，我有45分钟，嗯，
left about, so the kinda models people build with coreference.
离开了，所以人们用共同构建的模型。
And I hope to mention quickly four different ways that people have looked at coreference.
我希望能够迅速提到人们看待共识的四种不同方式。
I wanna tell you a teeny bit about classical rule-based coreference.
我想告诉你一些关于经典的基于规则的共识。
Um, then, um, mention- mention pair coreference.
嗯，那么，嗯，提一下 - 提及对共识。
Spend the most time on mention ranking systems which have
花费大部分时间在提及排名系统上
tended to be the easiest simple systems.
往往是最简单的简单系统。
And then just say a little bit about
然后再说一点
clustering systems which should be the right way to do
集群系统应该是正确的方法
it but in practice has been a way that's been hard to get the best performance from.
它实际上是一种难以从中获得最佳性能的方法。
Okay. So here's a bit of history.
好的。所以这里有一段历史。
Um, this guy here is Jerry Hobbs.
嗯，这家伙是Jerry Hobbs。
He just had his retirement party from University of Southern California last month.
他上个月刚刚从南加州大学参加退休派对。
Um, so Jerry Hobbs,
嗯，杰里霍布斯，
way back when, um,
回来的时候，嗯，
wrote a famous paper,
写了一篇名言，
it was in 1976 on coreference resolution.
它是在1976年的共识解决方案。
And in that paper, um, he proposed,
在那篇论文中，嗯，他提出，
um, what's normally now referred to as the Hobbs Algorithm.
嗯，现在通常被称为Hobbs算法。
But actually, um, in his paper,
但实际上，嗯，在他的论文中，
he refers to it as a naive algorithm.
他称之为天真的算法。
Um, and I'll come back to that distinction in just a moment.
嗯，我马上就会回到那个区别。
Um, but what the Hobbs algorithm was,
嗯，但Hobbs算法是什么，
is if you have a sentence- so actually I should say this,
如果你有一个句子 - 所以实际上我应该这样说，
this algorithm is just for finding the reference of pronouns.
该算法仅用于寻找代词的参考。
So one can extend out to other cases but the part I'm gonna show
所以我可以延伸到其他案例，但我要展示的部分
you is just the part for doing the reference of pronouns.
你只是做代词参考的部分。
So when you find out,
所以当你发现时，
find a pronoun and you wanna say what is it, um, coreferent with?
找到一个代名词，你想说的是什么，嗯，与...相关？
What you're going to do is run this mechanical algorithm
你要做的是运行这种机械算法
that's looking at a parse of a sentence and is working out what to do with it.
那是在查看一个句子的解析，并正在研究如何处理它。
Begin at the NP immediately dominating the pronoun,
从NP开始直接支配代词，
go up the trees or the first NP or S. Call this X and the path p,
上去树或第一个NP或S.叫这个X和路径p，
traverse along, ah, it goes on and on.
穿过，啊，它继续下去。
Um, there's more of it.
嗯，还有更多。
That was only the beginning of it.
那只是它的开始。
There are a lot more stages.
还有很多阶段。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
I'm not- I don't really wanna go into the details of this.
我不是 - 我真的不想详细介绍这一点。
Um, but, you know, to try and explain the flavor of it,
嗯，但是，你知道，试着解释它的味道，
here's a piece of text.
这是一段文字。
"Niall Ferguson is prolific,
“Niall Ferguson是多产的，
well-paid, and a snappy dresser.
高薪，和一个活泼的梳妆台。
Stephen Moss hated him."
斯蒂芬莫斯恨他。“
Um, and so if you can remember any of the steps of that algorithm,
嗯，如果你能记住那个算法的任何步骤，
here's our, um, pronoun him.
这是我们的，嗯，代名他。
Um, and then, what it said to do was begin at the NP,
嗯，然后，它所说的是从NP开始，
the noun phrase above the pronoun.
代词上方的名词短语。
And then it said, to go up to the first noun phrase or S above that,
然后它说，要达到上面的第一个名词短语或S，
um, here is the S above that.
嗯，这是上面的S.
Um, and then what you're meant to do is, from there,
嗯，然后你打算做的是，从那里，
you're meant to go left to right through stuff that came before that.
你打算通过之前的东西从左到右。
So there's a lot of cleverness in this handwritten algorithm.
所以这个手写算法有很多聪明之处。
You know, this is in the space of clever handwritten algorithms.
你知道，这是在聪明的手写算法的空间。
And so what this is reflecting is that you might just think you
所以这反映出你可能会想到你
should go to the closest thing to find reference,
应该去最接近的东西找到参考，
but actually if you have reference within the same sentence,
但实际上如果你在同一个句子中有引用，
it's much more common for the sort of
这种情况更为常见
highest syntactic roles to be what you're coreferent with.
最高的句法角色是你的共同作用。
So you're more likely to be coreferent with a subject than an object,
所以你更有可能成为一个主题而不是一个对象，
and you're more likely to be coreferent with an object than something like
并且你更有可能成为一个对象而不是类似的东西
a noun phrase and that's inside a prepositional phrase that follows the object.
一个名词短语，它位于跟随该对象的介词短语中。
So we're gonna start from the left here and we're gonna
所以我们要从左边开始，我们要去
say here's a noun phrase, Stephen Moss.
这里是一个名词短语，斯蒂芬莫斯。
That's the first one we come to.
这是我们第一次来到这里。
And then there's this clever bit of text that says,
然后有这个聪明的文字说，
um, traversal branches, um, below X,
嗯，遍历分支，嗯，在X下面，
that are to the left- left to right,
这是从左到右，
propose as antecedent and noun phrase, um,
提出作为先行词和名词短语，嗯，
that has a noun phrase or sentence between it's an ec- in the S. So it was saying,
在它之间有一个名词短语或句子，它是一个ec-在S.所以它说，
this will be a candidate,
这将是一个候选人，
if and only if,
当且仅当，
there's some other noun phrase or S in-between.
还有一些其他名词短语或中间的S.
Um, and so what that's saying is Stephen Moss hated him.
嗯，所以说斯蒂芬莫斯恨他。
It- this him cannot refer back to
它 - 这是他无法回头的
Stephen Moss and that sort of pretty much a fact of English syntax.
斯蒂芬·莫斯（Stephen Moss），这几乎是英语句法的一个事实。
But what it's wanting to do is distinguish between,
但它想要做的是区分，
another thing that we could have had here was
我们本可以做的另一件事是
a noun phrase that had another possessive noun phrase inside it.
一个名词短语，里面有另一个所有格名词短语。
Um, so if we had something like Stephen Moss's mother hated him, right?
嗯，所以如果我们有像斯蒂芬莫斯的母亲那样恨他，对吗？
Then the Stephen mother- Moss's mother hated him, then that would,
然后，斯蒂芬母亲 - 莫斯的母亲恨他，那就是，
in that case, it would be perfectly okay for him to be coreferent with Stephen Moss.
在那种情况下，他完全可以与斯蒂芬莫斯共同参与。
And the algorithm allows that because relative to
并且算法允许因为相对于
this noun phrase is another noun phrase above it and between.
这个名词短语是它上面和之间的另一个名词短语。
Okay. So that didn't work, um,
好的。那不起作用，嗯，
as an antece- as an antecedent,
作为一个先行者 - 作为先行者，
so then we go onto the next step of the algorithm.
那么我们进入算法的下一步。
And then, the next step says,
然后，下一步说，
we should proceed backwards through preceding sentences,
我们应该通过前面的句子倒退，
um, right to left.
嗯，从右到左。
And so that captures an important heuristic that proximity is actually
因此，它捕获了实际接近的重要启发式
a good heuristic to find coreference
找到共识的良好启发式方法
because coreference for pronouns is usually close by overall.
因为代词的共鸣通常是整体的。
And so we go to the first sentence back.
所以我们回到第一句话。
And then in this sentence, again,
然后在这句话中，
we go into within the sentence,
我们进入句子，
go left to right because there's the same kind of subject prominence role.
从左到右，因为有同样的主题突出角色。
And so we're gonna start in this sentence,
所以我们要从这句话开始，
and we're gonna say okay,
我们会说好的，
here's a noun phrase.
这是一个名词短语。
And now because we're in a different sentence,
而现在因为我们的句子不同，
there's nothing wrong with this one.
这个没什么不对。
So we say, aha,
所以我们说，啊哈，
we have a candidate, Niall Ferguson,
我们有一个候选人，Niall Ferguson，
um, is a possible antecedent and it's the first one we found.
嗯，是一个可能的前因，这是我们发现的第一个。
And therefore, we say that him refers back to Niall Ferguson.
因此，我们说他回到了Niall Ferguson。
And this algorithm actually gives the right answer,
而这个算法实际上给出了正确的答案，
if you could follow along all of that.
如果你能跟上这一切。
Um, though that sounds like, um,
嗯，虽然这听起来像，嗯，
horrible handwritten stuff.
可怕的手写的东西。
But, um, so Jerry Hobbs was aware of that this was horrible handwritten stuff,
但是，嗯，所以Jerry Hobbs意识到这是可怕的手写内容，
but he was interested in this algorithm for a couple of reasons.
但出于几个原因，他对这个算法很感兴趣。
I mean, reason one is, you know,
我的意思是，理由是，你知道，
this is actually one of the first places in natural language processing,
这实际上是自然语言处理的第一个地方，
that someone produced the baseline, right.
对，有人产生了基线，对。
In for final projects and elsewhere,
在最终项目和其他地方，
um, and stuff we gave you, right,
嗯，我们给你的东西，对，
it's seen now in NLP and other areas,
它现在在NLP和其他领域看到，
that anything you are doing,
那你在做什么，
the first thing you should do is have a baseline,
你应该做的第一件事是有一个基线，
a simple system and see how well it works.
一个简单的系统，看看它的工作情况。
And this was his simple rule-based system for doing coreference,
这是他基于规则的简单系统，用于进行共指，
um, and he wanted to observe that actually this baseline was pretty good.
嗯，他想观察到实际上这个基线非常好。
It actually gave the right answer a lot of the time.
它实际上在很多时候给出了正确答案。
And so the challenge was how to build a system that did better than this baseline.
因此，挑战在于如何建立一个比这个基线更好的系统。
And so he was well aware of it,
所以他很清楚这一点，
you know, it was a dumb algorithm,
你知道，这是一个愚蠢的算法，
but he proposed that as a good baseline for doing coreference resolution.
但他提出这是做共指消解的良好基线。
So what he was interested in,
所以他感兴趣的是，
um, remember that we're back in the 1970s here,
嗯，记得我们回到了20世纪70年代，
was how to do knowledge-based pronominal coreference resolution.
是如何做基于知识的代词共指解决。
And so, um, essentially what he was noticing is well,
所以，嗯，基本上他注意到的是，
these kinds of syntactic factors that I was mentioning prefer subjects,
我提到的这些句法因素更喜欢科目，
prefer close by, etc,
喜欢附近等等，
they're all useful predictors.
他们都是有用的预测者。
But there are lots of cases where they don't give the right answer,
但是很多情况下他们没有给出正确答案，
and to know when they give, when,
并知道他们什么时候给，
to know what's really the coreferent thing,
知道什么是真正的共同点，
you have to actually understand what's being described in the world.
你必须真正了解世界上正在描述的内容。
So if I have this sentence,
所以，如果我有这句话，
she poured water from the pitcher into the cup until it was full.
她把水从投手里倒进杯子里，直到它满了。
What is it coreferent with?
什么是共同的？
Cup.
杯子。
[NOISE] The cup.
[NOISE]杯子。
Thank you. [LAUGHTER] Okay.
谢谢。 [大笑]好的。
So that, it refers to the cup.
所以，它指的是杯子。
But then let's look at this example.
但接下来让我们来看看这个例子。
She poured water from the pitcher into the cup until it was empty.
她将水从投手倒入杯中，直到它空了。
What does it refer to?
它指的是什么？
The [OVERLAPPING].
[OVERLAPPING]。
The pitcher. [LAUGHTER] Okay.
投手。 [大笑]好的。
So the crucial thing to notice in these two sentences is,
所以在这两句话中要注意的关键是，
these sentences have identical syntactic structure, right.
这些句子具有相同的句法结构，对。
So Jerry Hobbs's algorithm can't possibly work,
所以Jerry Hobbs的算法不可行，
um, for both of these sentences.
嗯，对于这两个句子。
It's gonna work for one of them,
它会为其中一个工作，
but not the other one.
但不是另一个。
Um, since it's working from left to right within a sentence,
嗯，因为它在句子中从左到右工作，
it's gonna say the pitcher both times actually, right.
它实际上会说投手两次。
So you can't get the answer right by Jerry Hobbs' algorithm and Jerry believed,
因此，你无法通过Jerry Hobbs的算法得到正确答案，Jerry相信，
and still believes, um,
仍然相信，嗯，
that the only way to get these kind of examples right,
这是让这些例子正确的唯一方法，
is actually if you understand the world,
实际上，如果你了解这个世界，
and you actually know what's going on in the world,
你真的知道世界上发生了什么，
so you can see what, what this is talking about.
所以你可以看到这是什么，这是在谈论什么。
And there are lots of examples like this.
还有很多像这样的例子。
Um, this is another very famous example.
嗯，这是另一个非常着名的例子。
The city council refused the women a permit because they feared violence.
市议会拒绝给予妇女许可，因为她们害怕暴力。
Um, who does that they refer to?
嗯，他们指的是谁？
[inaudible].
[听不见的。
The city councilors.
市议员。
Um, but here's another sentence.
嗯，但这是另一句话。
The city council refused the women a permit because they advocated violence.
市议会拒绝给予妇女许可，因为她们主张暴力。
Who does that they refer to?
他们指的是谁？
The women.
女人。
The women. Okay. So this time it refers to the women.
女人。好的。所以这次是指女性。
Um, and again, you know,
嗯，你知道，
identical syntactic structure, it couldn't possibly be done right by the Hobbs algorithm.
相同的句法结构，不可能通过Hobbs算法完成。
Um, so this particular pair of examples,
嗯，所以这一对特例，
um, comes from Terry Winograd.
嗯，来自Terry Winograd。
Um, how long ti- uh,
嗯，多久了，
so Terry Winograd was originally an NLP faculty, um,
所以Terry Winograd最初是一名NLP教员，嗯，
he sort of got disillusioned with NLP because there wasn't making much progress, um,
他对NLP感到失望，因为没有取得多大进展，嗯，
and ventured off into the land of HCI,
并冒险进入HCI之地，
um, that became his career.
嗯，这成了他的职业生涯。
Um, but in his early work, um,
嗯，但在他早期的工作中，嗯，
he was interested in these phenomena,
他对这些现象感兴趣，
and came up with this example.
并想出了这个例子。
And so this example really stuck with people.
所以这个例子真的让人感到困惑。
And so these kind of contrasts are referred to by
所以这些对比被提及
other people as Winograd sentences or Winograd schema.
其他人作为Winograd句子或Winograd架构。
And so this is actually something that's interesting that's revived recently.
所以这实际上是有趣的，最近复活了。
Um, so Hector Le- Levesque, um,
嗯，所以Hector Le- Levesque，嗯，
wrote a paper, I guess five years ago now,
写了一篇论文，我猜五年前，
where he was trying to advocate for return to doing
在那里他试图倡导回归
more in the way of knowledge and world modeling and artificial intelligence,
更多的是知识和世界建模以及人工智能，
and arguing that there are lots of problems that you just
并且认为你有很多问题
can't solve by the kind of crude statistical methods,
用粗略的统计方法无法解决，
that our machine learning systems are using.
我们的机器学习系统正在使用。
And that you really needed to do more world understanding.
而且你真的需要做更多的世界理解。
And so he proposed that
所以他提出了这个建议
these Winograd schema would be a good te- alternative to the Turing test,
这些Winograd架构将是图灵测试的一个很好的替代品，
as a way of measuring intelligence.
作为衡量智力的一种方式。
And actually they're just coreference decisions, right.
实际上，它们只是共同决策，对吧。
So, um, so there's sort of a claim here that,
那么，嗯，所以这里有一种说法，
if you can do a coreference right 100 percent of the time,
如果你可以100％的时间做一个共识，
you've solved artificial intelligence in that you're, sort of you can,
你已经解决了人工智能，你可以，
can code knowledge of the world into coreference problems.
可以将世界知识编码成共识问题。
Um, yes so people have then tried to work on these Winograd schemas,
嗯，是的，所以人们试图研究这些Winograd模式，
and Levesque's feeling was, you know,
你知道，Levesque的感觉是，
you just couldn't do these,
你就是做不到这些，
um, using kind of,
嗯，使用的，
the kind of statistical factors, um,
那种统计因素，嗯，
that people put into their machine learning systems.
人们投入他们的机器学习系统。
He was partly wrong about that because subsequent work, um,
他对此有些不对，因为后来的工作，嗯，
both neural systems and otherwise has shown that actually you can
两个神经系统和其他已经表明，实际上你可以
get f- a nontrivial distance with these kind of problems because, you know,
得到f-这些问题的一个非常重要的距离，因为，你知道，
if it is the case,
如果是这样的话，
um, that, you know,
嗯，你知道，
you can somehow see enough examples,
你可以看到足够的例子，
where the city council refuses permits,
市议会拒绝许可，
fearing violence, you know.
害怕暴力，你知道。
If you've go- if you're collecting
如果你去，如果你正在收集
your neural language model over tens of billions of words,
你的神经语言模型超过数百亿字，
you might have seen some instances of things like that,
你可能已经看到过类似的事情，
and you could sort of predict it just on statistical patterning.
你可以根据统计模式预测它。
But the question is, you know,
但问题是，你知道，
how far can you actually get doing that,
你能在多大程度上做到这一点，
without having a bit more of a world model?
没有更多的世界模型？
And so that was, you know,
那就是，你知道，
what Hobbs was interested in way back in 1978.
霍布斯在1978年对此感兴趣。
So he wrote, the naive approach is quite good,
所以他写道，天真的做法非常好，
computationally speaking it will be a long time before a semantically based algorithm,
从计算上讲，在基于语义的算法之前需要很长时间，
is sophisticated enough to perform as well.
非常复杂，也可以表现得很好。
And these results set a very high standard for any other approach to aim for.
这些结果为任何其他目标方法设定了很高的标准。
He was totally right about that, um,
他是完全正确的，嗯，
that it really wasn't until the 2010s that anybody
它确实直到2010年才有人
managed to produce an algorithm for pronominal anaphora resolution,
设法产生代词回指分辨率的算法，
that outperformed the Hobbs algorithm.
其表现优于Hobbs算法。
Even though it was just, uh,
虽然只是，呃，
what he called a naive algorithm,
他称之为天真算法，
or he might call a crude set of linguistic rules.
或者他可以称之为粗略的语言规则。
Um, but he says,
嗯，但他说，
yet there is every reason to pursue a semantically based approach,
但是有充分理由采用基于语义的方法，
the naive algorithm does not work.
天真的算法不起作用。
Anyone can think of examples where it fails.
任何人都可以想到失败的例子。
In these cases it not only fails,
在这些情况下，它不仅失败，
it gives no indication that it has failed,
它没有表明它已经失败，
and offers no help in finding the real antecedent.
并没有帮助找到真正的先行者。
Um, so food for thought there.
嗯，那里有点值得思考。
Um, but, um, notwithstanding that,
嗯，但是，嗯，尽管如此，
I'm gonna just rush ahead at this point,
我现在要赶紧前进，
and tell you about some of the, um,
并告诉你一些，嗯，
statistical and neural algorithms,
统计和神经算法，
um, that have been used for coreference resolution.
嗯，已被用于共指消解。
So the simplest form of algorithm that's commonly used,
所以常用的最简单的算法形式，
is what is called mention pair models.
就是所谓的提对模型。
So what we mean by mention pair models is, um,
所以提到对模型我们的意思是，嗯，
we are gonna take pairs of mentions,
我们要采取一对提及，
and we're gonna train a binary classifier that says,
我们要训练一个二进制分类器说，
is coreferent or isn't coreferent.
是共同的或不是共同的。
And so then we're gonna proceed left to right through the text.
然后我们将从文本中左右移动。
And every time we get to a new mention,
每当我们重新提到时，
we're gonna then evaluate our classifier with respect to every preceding mention,
然后，我们将根据之前的每一个提及来评估我们的分类器，
and we're gonna say, are they coreferent?
我们会说，他们是否具有共识？
And it's gonna say yes or no.
它会说是或否。
And we're gonna find out that some of them.
而且我们会发现其中的一些。
It says yes for, um,
它是的，是的，嗯，
I voted for Nader because he was like, most aligned with my value.
我投票支持Nader，因为他很喜欢，与我的价值最相符。
She said, if we have a good classifier,
她说，如果我们有一个好的分类器，
it will say yes to the two bu- blue ones and not to the rest of them.
它会对两个蓝色的那个说“是”而不是其他的。
Um, and so then we'll have at training time,
嗯，那么我们将在训练时间，
negative examples that Nader and he are negative examples.
纳德和他是负面例子的负面例子。
[NOISE] So if you have data marked for coreference,
[NOISE]因此，如果您有标记为共参照的数据，
we have the sort of positive and negative examples,
我们有一些积极和消极的例子，
and we can train a model.
我们可以训练一个模型。
And so for training a model,
因此，对于训练模型，
we have a sort of the classifier outcome is one or zero,
我们有一种分类器结果是一个或零，
based on whether two mentions are coreferent.
基于两个提及是否具有共识性。
We're gonna have a coreference model that
我们将有一个共同参与模型
predicts the probability of them being coreferent.
预测他们被提出的概率。
And we're gonna train it with the same kind of cross entropy loss,
而且我们将用同样的交叉熵损失训练它，
we've used other places and, um,
我们用过其他地方了，嗯，
try and learn a model that predicts coreference.
尝试学习预测共识的模型。
And so then when we get to test time, um,
那么当我们开始测试时，嗯，
and we have a piece of text with mentions, um,
我们有一段文字提及，嗯，
we're gonna run this classifier and it's gonna say,
我们要运行这个分类器，它会说，
um, yes or no, with some probability.
嗯，是或否，有一定概率。
And if we pick a threshold like 0,5,
如果我们选择像0,5这样的阈值，
we'll add certain coreference links.
我们将添加某些共享链接。
And that sort of looks pretty good.
而那种看起来很不错。
Um, but we're gonna sort of complete it off by saying well,
嗯，但是我们可以通过说得好来完成它，
if A is coreferent to B and B is K coreferent to C. Then really
如果A对B是共同的，那么B就是K对C的贡献。那么真的
also A is coreferent to C. So we're gonna do a transitive closure,
A也是C的共同点。所以我们要做一个传递闭包，
and that will give us our clustering.
这将为我们提供聚类。
Um, note here that there's a certain danger in this.
嗯，请注意这里有一定的危险。
Because this means, if we make,
因为这意味着，如果我们这样做，
since we're sor- with the transitive closure,
既然我们是传统的封闭，
that's always adding clustering links.
这总是添加群集链接。
And so that means the danger is that we're gonna over cluster,
所以这意味着危险就是我们要过度集群，
because if we make a single mistake and we link things that should be kept separate.
因为如果我们犯了一个错误，我们将应该保持分开的事物联系起来。
So for example, if we wrongly said,
例如，如果我们错误地说，
he and my are coreferent,
他和我是共同的，
then everything of this, um,
那么这一切，嗯，
discourse would collapse together into one cluster,
话语会一起聚集成一个群集，
and everything would be deemed coreferent.
一切都将被视为共同的。
Okay, um, and this,
好的，嗯，这个，
something that I haven't really emphasized, but comes up,
我没有真正强调的东西，但是出现了，
is well, there's some mentions that are coreferent to nothing, right.
是的，有一些提及对任何事都没有，对吧。
In the Shruthi Rao story, there was a park,
在Shruthi Rao故事中，有一个公园，
which was just mentioned once in the text, and so on,
在文中刚刚提到过一次，等等，
in this form of algorithm,
在这种形式的算法中，
what we'd like the classifier to say is, no,
我们希望分类器说的是，不，
no, no, no, no,
不不不不，
for all of the decisions.
对于所有的决定。
And so it's deemed coreferent to nothing.
所以它被视为无所谓。
And then it's just a singleton mention.
然后它只是一个单身人士提到。
This sort of works,
这种作品，
but it hasn't proven to be the best way of doing coreference.
但它并没有被证明是做共识的最佳方式。
And a lot of the reason why it's not the best way to do coreference
并且很多原因导致它不是做共识的最佳方式
is because we have this phenomenon of anaphora where we have textural dependence.
是因为我们有这种回指现象，我们有纹理依赖。
A lot of the time,
很多时候，
it seems that we're not really,
好像我们不是真的，
um, what- sort of wanting to make this all coreference decisions.
嗯，什么样的想要做出所有的共同决策。
We'd like to make the anaphora decisions of textural dependence.
我们想做出关于纹理依赖的回指决定。
So we'd like to say that he is,
所以我们想说他是，
um, dependent on Nader and my is dependent on I.
嗯，依赖于纳德而我依赖于我。
These are anaphora relationships.
这些是回指关系。
So we'd like to just choose one example of what is this anaphora relationship.
所以我们只想选择一个这个回指关系的例子。
And so that's led to people then looking at what is called,
所以这导致人们看到所谓的，
um, Mention Pair Models, right?
嗯，提到对模型，对吧？
That the problem is that if we have a long document with lots of mentions,
问题是，如果我们有一个很长的文件提到很多，
um, that we want to not be saying- trying to find all of them and say, yes.
嗯，我们不想说 - 试图找到所有这些并说，是的。
We just want to be saying there's a particular- we
我们只想说有一个特别的 - 我们
just want to be saying that there's a particular one.
只是想说有一个特定的。
So for the he at the end here,
所以对他来说，
its anaphor relationship is back to Nader and you don't wanna be trying to say this
它的回指关系又回到了纳德，你不想试图这样说
he is also coreferent back to all of these other things that are earlier in the text.
他还回顾了本文前面提到的所有其他事情。
So it's not something that's been explored much.
所以这不是一个被探索过的东西。
But arguably, this is a case again,
但可以说，这又是一个案例，
where you should be separating coreference from anaphors because for anaphors it seems like
在哪里你应该将共鸣从分析中分离出来，因为它似乎就像是一样
the right way to think is that they have
正确的思考方式是他们有
one prior thing in the text that they're textually dependent on.
文本中的一个先例是它们在文本上依赖于它们。
Whereas true coreferents, when you just have various mentions in the text of Ralph Nader,
而真正的共同主义者，当你在拉尔夫纳德的文本中有各种各样的提及时，
this Ralph Nader that,
这个Ralph Nader那个，
Nader did that, those aren't textually dependent
纳德这样做了，那些不依赖于文本
and they should all be being grouped together as coreferents.
他们都应该被归为一个共同的人。
Um, but our models sort of don't normally try and do some one way and some the other way,
嗯，但我们的模型通常不会尝试做某种方式，而另一种方式，
but you choose one of the models.
但你选择其中一个型号。
So in the other one,
所以在另一个，
we do it for- to do the other way,
我们这样做是为了做另一种方式，
you do what's mention rankings.
你做什么提到排名。
So for mention ranking,
所以提到排名，
the idea is for each mention,
每个提到的想法，
we're going to find- try and find it
我们将找到并找到它
an antecedent that comes before- before it in the text,
在文本之前出现的先行词，
that is- that it is, um,
就是这样，嗯，
coreferent with, and we're going to make a one of N decision.
与...相关，我们将做出N决定之一。
So that when we see she here,
所以，当我们看到她在这里，
we're going to say,
我们要说，
"Okay, um, what is this coreferent with?"
“好吧，嗯，这个共同点是什么？”
And we're going to pick one thing that it's coreferent
而且我们要选择一个它是共同的东西
with even though there might be others in the text.
尽管文中可能还有其他人。
Um, so if we're doing that,
嗯，如果我们这样做，
we then have a problem with singleton mentions because if
然后我们遇到单例提及的问题，因为如果
we're trying to- for every mention we find say,
我们试图 - 我们发现每一次提到，
choose the thing that came before it in the text with which it's coreferent,
选择它所依据的文本中出现的东西，
the right answer might be that there's no such thing.
正确的答案可能是没有这样的事情。
So what we do is we add
所以我们要做的就是添加
one additional dummy mention right at the front here, the NA mention.
NA提到的另一个虚拟提及就在前面。
So one choice is you're gonna say there isn't anything preceding.
所以一个选择是你会说没有任何事情在前面。
So effectively, when you get to I,
如此有效，当你到达我的时候，
since this is, um, the first, um,
因为这是，嗯，第一个，嗯，
real mention in the text,
在文中真实提到，
you're necessarily gonna choose as,
你一定会选择的，
um, its antecedent NA.
嗯，它的前身NA。
You then go on to Nader and you have two choices.
然后你继续前往Nader，你有两个选择。
You can either say it's coreferent to I or it's coreferent to NA.
你可以说它对我来说是共同的，或者它对NA来说是共同的。
I, it's a new mention- a new entity that's being mentioned in the text and
我，这是一个新的提及 - 一个新的实体，正在文中提到和
the right answer is it's a new mention in- a new entity being mentioned in the text.
正确的答案是在文中提到的新实体中的新提及。
Then you get to he and now you have three choices,
然后你到了他，现在你有三个选择，
and the right thing is to say that it's coreferent to Nader.
而正确的说法是它对纳德来说是共同的。
Okay. Um, so this time,
好的。嗯，这次，
it's- for training our models,
它 - 用于训练我们的模型，
it's sort of the same, um,
它有点相同，嗯，
apart from this, sort of this different one of semantics.
除此之外，还有一种不同的语义。
So now- previously, we wanted to say that for our, um,
所以现在 - 以前，我们想对我们说，嗯，
mention pair classifier that is going to try and classify I and she,
提及对我和她进行分类的对分类器，
and my and she,
而我和她，
and both of them had to get a high score,
他们俩都得分高，
where now it's sufficient that just one of them gets
现在只需其中一个就可以了
a high score because that's sort of enough for us to do.
高分，因为这对我们来说足够了。
So what we're gonna use is our good old softmax and so for she,
所以我们要使用的是我们的老式softmax，所以对她来说，
we're gonna put a softmax over the antecedents.
我们要在这些前因上加上softmax。
And our hope is simply that we get a high probability with one of the antecedents,
而我们的希望很简单，就是我们很有可能获得一个前因，
if it has an antecedent or a high score with NA,
如果它有NA的前因或高分，
if it doesn't have any prior referents.
如果它没有任何先前的指示物。
And so then when we're doing classification at run-time,
那么当我们在运行时进行分类时，
we're going to sort of add only the highest scoring coreference link.
我们将只添加得分最高的共同参考链接。
So that means we train it just slightly
所以这意味着我们只是略微训练它
differently because now what we're going to do is that,
不同，因为现在我们要做的是，
when we're- what we're wanting to say is,
当我们 - 我们想要说的是，
we want a high score of coreference between at least one of the antecedents.
我们希望至少有一个前因之间有很高的共识。
And so one possible model is,
一个可能的模型是，
we can maximize this probability.
我们可以最大化这个概率。
So for the ones that are coreferent in the gold standard data,
那么对于那些在黄金标准数据中具有共同意义的数据，
we want the sum of their assigned probabilities to be high.
我们希望它们指定概率的总和很高。
And so what that means is that it's sort of sufficient if we have,
所以这意味着，如果我们拥有，那就足够了，
um, one of them giving
嗯，其中一个给予
a high probability and they don't all have to give a high probability.
概率很高，并不是所有人都必须给出高概率。
So providing it's giving 0,9 probability,
因此，它提供0,9概率，
say it a one of the correct antecedents,
说这是一个正确的前因，
we're getting a high score.
我们获得了高分。
Okay. So we're gonna turn that into a loss function in the kind of
好的。因此，我们将把它变成一种损失函数
standard way we do in which we take log probabilities,
我们采用标准方式记录日志概率，
um, and then we want to, um,
嗯，然后我们想，嗯，
or negative log probabilities to give us
或负日志概率给我们
a loss and then we're wanting to minimize that loss.
损失然后我们想要减少损失。
So with the mention ranking model,
所以提到排名模型，
um, at test time,
嗯，在考试时间，
it's pretty much the same,
它几乎一样，
but our softmax classifier is just going to assign one antecedent for each mention.
但是我们的softmax分类器只是为每次提及分配一个前提。
And so we're then gonna hope that those sort of give us the kind
所以我们希望那些给我们的那种
of clusters that we want and there's no subsequent clustering phase.
我们想要的集群，没有后续的集群阶段。
So there's a big part of this that I left out which was,
所以我遗漏的很大一部分是，
I've just said, "Okay,
我刚才说，“好的，
we have this probability of MI and MJ as the- are they coreferent?"
我们有MI和MJ的概率 - 他们是共同的吗？“
But I've sort of said, zero as to
但我有点说，零
how you can determine whether they're coreferent or not.
你如何确定他们是否是共同的。
Um, so briefly, um,
嗯，简单地说，嗯，
here- here's the classical way of doing it.
这里 - 这是经典的做法。
The classical way of doing it is,
经典的做法是，
you had a whole bunch of features and you had
你拥有一大堆功能
a feature based statistical classifier which gave a score.
基于特征的统计分类器，给出了分数。
And these are the kind of features you could use.
这些是您可以使用的功能。
So there are sort of strong features of person, number, gender agreement.
因此，人，数量，性别协议有一些强大的特征。
So if you have a masculine or feminine pronoun,
所以，如果你有男性或女性代名词，
you wanna find an appropriate antecedent for it.
你想找到一个合适的先行者。
There are weaker, um, semantic compatibility features.
有较弱的，嗯，语义兼容性功能。
So the mining conglomerate, the company,
那么矿业集团，公司，
the conglomerate might be sort of similar to a company.
该集团可能有点类似于公司。
You could use something like word2vec similarity and assess that.
你可以使用像word2vec相似的东西并评估它。
There are syntactic constraints.
有句法约束。
So this is then kind of like, um,
所以这就像是，嗯，
what Hobbs's algorithm was all about us working out
Hobbs的算法是关于我们锻炼的
how likely different syntactic configurations are gonna mean coreference.
不同的句法配置有多大可能意味着共同参与。
And indeed it is the case, you know,
事实确实如此，你知道，
that a lot of these feature-based systems used Hobbs' algorithm as a feature inside
很多这些基于特征的系统都使用Hobbs的算法作为内部特征
the system that was weighted and was normally a very strong feature to decide coreference.
加权的系统通常是决定共同参与的一个非常强大的功能。
Um, there are lots of other things you can put in as features.
嗯，还有很多其他东西你可以作为功能。
Um, recency.
嗯，新近。
So John went to a movie,
约翰去看电影，
Jack went as well,
杰克去了，
he was not busy.
他不忙。
The most likely referent for he is the closer candidate Jack.
他最有可能的参考对象是杰克。
Um, I've mentioned subjects are more likely to be, um, the antecedent.
嗯，我提到的主题更有可能是，嗯，先行者。
John went to a movie with Jack,
约翰和杰克一起去看电影，
he was not busy.
他不忙。
Um, John seems a more likely antecedent.
嗯，约翰似乎更有可能是先行者。
So that's the sort of subject preference.
这就是主题偏好。
There's also a parallelism preference.
还存在并行性偏好。
So John went with Jack to a movie,
所以约翰和杰克一起去看电影，
Joe went with him to a bar.
乔和他一起去了一家酒吧。
I think it's sort of reasonable to think that him there is probably Jack,
我觉得有可能认为他可能是杰克，
and that's sort of for parallelism reasons as opposed to going with the subject.
这与并行主义的原因相反，而不是与主题相关。
So there are various kind of linguistic features and constraints and so on,
所以有各种语言特征和约束等等，
and you can throw these all into a statistical classifier and that's
你可以将这些全部投入到统计分类器中
sort of 2000s decade coref systems as to how they're built.
关于它们如何构建的2000年代十年核心系统。
Um, more recently, people have built neural systems.
嗯，最近，人们建立了神经系统。
And so for these,
对于这些，
we are kind of normally using the same kind of embeddings.
我们通常使用相同类型的嵌入。
So we'll have a candidate antecedent that will have embeddings,
所以我们将有一个候选先行者，将有嵌入，
we'll have a mention that has embeddings.
我们会提到嵌入式。
And this will be something like
这将是类似的东西
average word vectors or something like that for the mention.
平均单词向量或类似的东西。
And we're gonna feed these into a neural network that will give us our score.
我们将把它们送入一个能给我们分数的神经网络。
But what you find is that
但你发现的是
most of these systems as well as having something like word vectors,
大多数这些系统以及像word vector这样的东西，
they also have additional features, um,
他们还有其他功能，嗯，
and these features still capture some of
而这些功能仍然捕获了一些
the things that were in the feature-based statistical classifiers.
基于特征的统计分类器中的内容。
So there will be often features that reflect things like,
因此，通常会有一些功能可以反映出像
what grammatical relation does this mention have? Is it a subject?
这提到了什么语法关系？这是一个主题吗？
Is it an object?
它是一个对象吗？
That's something you could put into the features of a mention.
这是你可以提到的功能。
But then, closer things are more likely to be coreferent.
但是，更接近的事情更有可能是共同的。
So you might have additional features here which record how far apart dimensions are,
所以你可能在这里有额外的功能记录了相距多远的尺寸，
and those things get thrown in as well.
那些东西也被抛入其中。
Um, and so these kind of features are still important even in neural systems.
嗯，所以即使在神经系统中，这些特征仍然很重要。
And so I'll skip ahead now and show you a bit about, um,
所以我现在就跳过去向你展示一下，嗯，
what is the kind of current state of the art for coreference resolution,
什么是当前的共参考分辨率技术，
and this was a system that was done at the University of Washington in
这是一个在华盛顿大学完成的系统
2017 by Kenton Lee and assorted other, um, authors.
2017年作者：Kenton Lee和其他作者。
Um, so the goal here was to produce an end-to-end coreference system that it was text in,
嗯，所以这里的目标是生成一个端到端的共享系统，它是文本，
um, mention clusters that are coreferent out.
嗯，提一下共同提出的集群。
Um, and so they're wanting to use sort of a more complex
嗯，所以他们想要使用更复杂的东西
neural network that can do the whole thing end-to-end. So I'll go through,
神经网络，可以做到端到端的整个事情。所以我会通过，
um, the steps of that.
嗯，其中的步骤。
So the first step is we just start off with words.
所以第一步是我们从言语开始。
And so for each word,
对于每个单词，
we're going to look up a word embedding for it and that's in other stuff we've seen.
我们要查找一个嵌入它的单词，这是我们见过的其他内容。
We're also going to put in a character level CNN,
我们还将加入CNN的角色级别，
and the two of those concatenated are going to give the representation of each token.
并且这两个连接的将给出每个标记的表示。
That much should look familiar.
这应该看起来很熟悉。
Okay. Then after that,
好的。然后，
we're going to run a deep bidirectional LSTM back and forth across the sentence.
我们将在整个句子中来回运行深度双向LSTM。
Again, that should look familiar from stuff that we've seen before.
再说一遍，我们以前见过的东西看起来应该很熟悉。
Um, the next step gets us a bit into doing something more special, um,
嗯，下一步让我们做一些更特别的事情，嗯，
For coreference.
对于共同参与。
So what they wanted to do after that is have a representation for spans.
所以他们想要做的就是有跨度的代表。
And so by span,
因此，跨度，
we mean any contiguous subphrase of the word, of the sentence.
我们指的是句子中任何单词的连续子句。
So this is a span.
所以这是一个跨度。
This is a span.
这是一个跨度。
Electric said the postal is a span, every sub-sequence.
电力称邮政是一个跨度，每个子序列。
Um, so I'll come back to that.
嗯，我会回来的。
But, you know, they'll- in principle,
但是，你知道，他们原则上会
you're working this out for every sub-sequence.
你正在为每个子序列工作。
So for every sub-sequence,
所以对于每个子序列，
they want to come up with a span representation.
他们想要提出跨度表示。
And so this span representation is going to be in three parts,
所以这个跨度表示将分为三个部分，
um, that represent one of these sub-sequences.
嗯，代表这些子序列之一。
Um, so each of these will get its own representation.
嗯，所以每个人都会得到自己的代表。
And so the question is, what?
所以问题是，什么？
And so we have this span representation,
所以我们有这个跨度表示，
and it's gonna be in these three parts here.
这将是这三个部分。
Um, so what these parts are is,
嗯，这些部分是什么，
well, first of all,
好吧，首先，
we're going to have a representation, um,
我们要有一个代表，嗯，
which is just looking at the first word of
这只是看第一个字
the span and the last word of the span according to the BiLSTM.
根据BiLSTM，跨度和跨度的最后一个字。
So if we're looking at the span, the postal service,
所以，如果我们正在考虑跨度，邮政服务，
we're going to take this BiLSTM and
我们将采用这种BiLSTM和
this BiLSTM and use them as part of the representation of the span.
这个BiLSTM并将它们用作跨度表示的一部分。
Um, that's a good start,
嗯，这是一个好的开始，
but then they actually do something a little tricky.
但他们实际上做了一些有点棘手的事情。
So kind of like when we're doing dependency parsing, the idea was,
有点像我们在进行依赖解析时，这个想法是，
well, phrases are going to have a headword,
好吧，短语会有一个标题，
um, so that if it's,
嗯，如果是的话，
um, you know, my younger sister that the headword of that is sister,
嗯，你知道，我的妹妹，那个标题是妹妹，
and there- if it's something like the goat in the corner of the field,
而且 - 如果它像田野角落里的山羊，
the headword of that is going to be goat.
这个词的标题是山羊。
So they want to find a way of capturing headwords out of the text.
因此，他们希望找到一种从文本中捕获词条的方法。
Um, and so what they're going to do for that is use attention.
嗯，所以他们要为此做的是使用注意力。
So they're going to say we have this span, the postal service,
所以他们会说我们有这个跨度，邮政服务，
and we're going to use attention as
我们将把注意力作为
a span internal mechanism to sort of approximate a head.
一个跨度内部机制来排序近似一个头。
So what we're going to do, uh, here,
那么我们要做什么，呃，在这里，
what we're going to do is we're going to want to
我们要做的就是我们想要的
learn attention weights, I'm just gonna, yeah.
学习注意力量，我会，是的。
Um, what we're gonna do is for this span, um,
嗯，我们要做的就是这个跨度，嗯，
we're going to be learning based on the hope,
我们将基于希望学习，
the ends of the span which words to pay how much attention to.
跨度的两端要支付多少注意力。
So we're gonna put attention weights on the different words,
所以我们要把注意力放在不同的词上，
and then we're going to, in the usual attention way,
然后我们将以通常的注意方式，
make this weighted sum of having put the word pair-
把这个单词对的加权总和 -
the bidirectional LSTM pairs through a feed-forward network and end
双向LSTM通过前馈网络对结束
up with this new representation of a weighted representation.
这种加权表示的新表示。
And the hope is that in this case,
希望是在这种情况下，
most of the weight will go on this final servers,
大部分的重量将放在最终的服务器上，
which will be the headword.
这将是标题。
But there'll be sort of distributed across it.
但是它会有分布。
And so that gives them a model of
所以这给了他们一个模型
sort of mentions that use both ends and hope to find the key word of the mention.
提到使用两端并希望找到提及的关键词。
Okay. Um, so, um,
好的。嗯，恩，嗯，
that's two-thirds of the span,
这是跨度的三分之二，
but they still have over here these additional features.
但他们仍然有这些额外的功能。
And so they still have some additional features.
因此他们仍然有一些额外的功能。
They want to be able to mark speakers and addressees.
他们希望能够标记扬声器和收件人。
Um, they want to mark other things like the grammatical role.
嗯，他们想要标记其他东西，比如语法角色。
But if things occur, you know,
但是如果事情发生了，你知道，
it is still useful to have some additional features.
拥有一些额外的功能仍然很有用。
And so what they do is,
所以他们做的是，
this is a representation of each span,
这是每个跨度的表示，
and then they're going to want to say are two spans coreferent.
然后他们想要说的是两个跨度的共同点。
And so they're going to have one score for the two, two split, each of two spans,
因此，他们将获得两个分数，两个分裂，每个两个跨度，
which is essentially saying,
这基本上是说，
is that a good mention?
这是一个很好的提及？
And then you're going to have scores of,
然后你会得到几十分，
do they look coreferent?
他们看起来很干净吗？
And so having calculated these representations for each span,
因此计算了每个跨度的这些表示，
you're running three- through things through a fully connected feed-forward network,
你通过一个完全连接的前馈网络运行三个东西，
multiplying by a weight factor,
乘以权重因子，
and that's giving you, uh,
那是给你的，呃，
is that a good mention score?
这是一个很好的提分吗？
And then for are they coreferent,
然后是因为他们是共同的，
you're taking two spans,
你需要两个跨度，
the pointwise Hadamard product of two spans and
两个跨度和点的Hadamard积分
some extra features like distance apart in
一些额外的功能，如距离分开
the text and putting them through another neural network,
文本并通过另一个神经网络，
and that's then giving you, are
那是给你的，是的
these two spans coreferent?
这两个跨度有何结合？
But all of these pieces,
但所有这些，
um, give you an overall loss function.
嗯，给你一个整体的损失功能。
So you can say that your model is, um, okay.
所以你可以说你的模型是，好吧。
We're going to run these LSTMs,
我们要运行这些LSTM，
we're going to take all spans,
我们要采取所有跨度，
we're going to score this,
我们打算得分，
and we know the gold answer for our coreference system.
我们知道我们的共同参与系统的黄金答案。
And so we want to be predicting things that are coreferent and have
所以我们想要预测那些具有共同意义的东西
a loss based on the probability that we calculate with these scores,
基于我们用这些分数计算的概率的损失，
um, as I had mentioned,
嗯，正如我所提到的，
ranking model using a softmax loss like before.
使用像之前一样的softmax损失的排名模型。
So if you put all of this together and train it end to end,
所以，如果你将所有这些放在一起并进行端到端的训练，
you've got a whole coreference system that goes from words to coreference decisions.
你有一个完整的共享系统，从单词到共同决策。
Um, there's a huge problem with that,
嗯，这有一个很大的问题，
um, which is if you actually applied this naively, well,
嗯，如果你真的应用这个天真，那么，
the problem is the number of spans in a piece of
问题是一块中的跨度数量
text is the square of the length of the text in words.
text是文字长度的平方。
And so therefore, if you're making coreference decisions,
因此，如果您正在制定共识决策，
which are between, um, pairs of spans,
介于两个跨度之间，
you've then got an algorithm that's, um,
你有一个算法，嗯，
O- OT to the fourth,
O- OT到第四，
where the length of the text is T words.
其中文本的长度是T字。
So that's sort of really, really computationally impractical.
所以这真的，在计算上是不切实际的。
So at this point,
所以在这一点上，
they sort of say, well, actually,
他们有点说，其实，
we do want to use our mouths a little and we want to work out
我们确实想要用一点口气，我们想要锻炼身体
how likely different things are to be mentions.
提到不同的东西的可能性有多大。
So effectively, um, then they're putting in a lot of pruning to
如此有效，嗯，然后他们正在进行大量的修剪
decide which spans are actually things that they want to consider in their model.
确定哪些跨度实际上是他们想要在模型中考虑的事情。
And so at this point, in some sense,
所以在这一点上，从某种意义上说，
it's a little bit of a cheat, right?
这有点像作弊，对吧？
Because really this pruning step here is okay,
因为这里的修剪步骤真的没问题，
we're going to stick in
我们要坚持下去
a mention detection module,
提及检测模块，
um, just like a conventional system.
嗯，就像传统的系统一样。
Um, but the prettiness of it is in terms of
嗯，但它的漂亮就是
the algor- in terms of the loss function that's defined.
关于定义的损失函数的算法。
The loss function is really defined end to end from just a sequence of
损失函数实际上是从一系列的端到端端到端定义的
tokens through to the mention ranking decisions.
标记到提及排名决定。
And so it is an end-to-end model,
所以这是一个端到端的模型，
even though in practice to make it practical,
即使在实践中使其变得实用，
you have to have something like a mention detector to get it to work.
你必须有类似提及探测器的东西让它工作。
Okay. Pause for breath. Um, yeah,
好的。暂停呼吸。嗯，是的，
so there's one last.
所以还有最后一个。
So we've done sort of mention pair model and mention ranking model.
所以我们已经提到了一对提模型和提及排名模型。
Um, and so for both of those,
嗯，对于这两个人，
you're just taking individual mentions and saying,
你只是个别提及说，
here's another mention, what,
这是另一个提及，什么，
what shall I do with it?
我该怎么办？
Let's look at mentions and see if we're coreferent to each other.
让我们看看提及，看看我们是否相互依存。
And that there's no real concept of entities which are clusters of mentions.
并且没有真正的实体概念是提及的集群。
You're just making these sort of one-off decisions
你只是在做这些一次性的决定
between pairs of mentions, and somehow,
提到之间，不知何故，
sort of the entities as clusters just
将实体排序为集群
emerge as a consequence of those mention pair decisions.
由于那些提及配对决定而出现。
So there's been this sort of long-standing feeling that,
所以有这种长期存在的感觉，
oh that can't really be right,
哦，这真的不对，
the right way to do coreference must be really to do it as a clustering task,
做共识的正确方法必须真正作为一个集群任务，
and people often refer to this as saying,
人们经常提到这一点，
we want entities as first-class citizens.
我们希望实体成为一等公民。
So we want to be,
所以我们想要，
sort of putting together mentions into clusters that represent the entities.
将提及组合成代表实体的集群。
And the obvious way to do that is to do a kind of bottom-up agglomerative clustering.
显而易见的方法是做一种自下而上的凝聚聚类。
So you start off by saying,
所以你先说，
each mention is its own singleton cluster,
每次提到都是自己的单身人群
and then you're making decisions to merge clu- clusters which is initially,
然后你决定合并最初的clu-clusters
um, saying two mentions are coreferent.
嗯，说两个提及是共同的。
But as you go on with it,
但随着你的继续，
you're then making decisions that two clusters are coreferent or not.
然后你决定两个集群是否是共同的。
So the idea here is you'll have a piece of text,
所以这里的想法是你会有一段文字，
Google recently blah blah blah blah,
谷歌最近等等等等等等等等，
the company announced Google Plus, blah blah blah blah,
该公司宣布推出Google Plus，等等等等等等等等。
the product features blah blah blah blah.
产品功能等等等等等等。
And so you have here some mentions.
所以你在这里有一些提及。
And so what you're going to do is start off saying that okay,
所以你要做的就是开始说那没关系，
there are these four mentions that each their own cluster.
有四个提到每个他们自己的集群。
And then what we're gonna do,
那么我们要做什么，
is we're going to make some decisions.
我们要做出一些决定吗？
Um, so we might decide that these two clusters
嗯，所以我们可能会决定这两个集群
are coreferent and merge them into one cluster.
是共同的，并将它们合并为一个集群。
And then we might decide that these two,
然后我们可能决定这两个，
um, clusters are coreferent and merge them into one cluster.
嗯，集群是共同的，并将它们合并为一个集群。
And so we're progressively clustering.
所以我们逐步聚类。
And so then, we're going to look at these two clusters,
那么，我们将看看这两个集群，
cluster one and cluster two, and say,
集群一和集群二，并说，
no we don't think those ones are coreferent,
不，我们不认为那些是共同的，
and therefore we're going to keep them apart.
因此我们要将它们分开。
And so your, your coreference algorithm stops when there's nothing left to merge.
因此，当没有任何东西要合并时，你的共参数算法会停止。
And the reason why people think that this is the right thing to do is,
人们认为这是正确的事情的原因是，
the feeling is that if we sort of build partial clusters like this,
感觉是，如果我们构建像这样的部分集群，
that you'll be able to do a better job.
你将能够做得更好。
Because if I just sort of say,
因为如果我只是说，
well here are two mentions,
这里有两个提及，
Google and Google Plus,
Google和Google Plus，
should they be regarded as co- coreferent or not?
他们应该被视为共同参与吗？
Um, well, since you're smart human beings,
嗯，既然你是聪明的人，
and know what Google is and know what Google Plus is,
并了解Google是什么，知道Google Plus是什么，
of course you'll answer no, of course not.
当然你不会回答不，当然不是。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
if you're just a computer trying to make a decision,
如果你只是一台试图做出决定的电脑，
it's sort of hard to know the right answer,
很难知道正确的答案，
because there are lots of other cases when there are shortenings,
因为有很多其他的情况，当有缩短时，
where the right answer is that they're coreferent, right.
正确的答案是，他们是共同的，对。
Because if this is being Google and Google Corp,
因为如果这是谷歌和谷歌公司，
then it would have been right to regard them as coreferent.
那么将它们视为共同的是正确的。
Or if it was sort of, um,
或者，如果它是那种，嗯，
something like Hillary Clinton and Hillary,
像希拉里克林顿和希拉里这样的东西，
it would have been right to regard them as coreferent.
将它们视为共识是正确的。
So it can often be kind of hard to tell what's coreferent.
因此，通常很难分辨出什么是共同的。
Um, but the hope is that,
嗯，但希望是，
if you've made some of the easy decisions first,
如果你先做了一些简单的决定，
so if you decide Google and the company are coreferent
所以如果你决定谷歌和公司是共同的
and Google Plus and the product are coreferent,
和谷歌Plus和产品是共同的，
then it should be much easier to tell and to say,
然后它应该更容易分辨和说，
well product and company,
好产品和公司，
they're definitely different things.
他们肯定是不同的东西。
And therefore we should keep these things separate.
因此我们应该将这些事情分开。
Um, and so that is the goal,
嗯，这就是目标，
and so to follow that goal,
所以要遵循这个目标，
the kind of models people build.
人们建立的模型。
And this was actually a model that Kevin Clark is one of the PhD students here,
这实际上是Kevin Clark是这里的博士生之一，
um, and we did a couple of years ago.
嗯，我们几年前做过。
The idea was well,
这个想法很好，
what we're going to do is,
我们要做的是，
we're initially going to consider mentioned pairs,
我们最初会考虑提到的对，
and build some kind of distributed, mention pair representation,
并构建某种分布式提及对表示，
which is kind of similar to what we were doing previously with the previous models.
这与我们之前使用之前的型号所做的类似。
But we're then going to go beyond that and come up with cluster representations.
但是我们将超越它并提出集群表示。
And then we can look at cluster pair representations.
然后我们可以看一下集群对表示。
And we would hope that by looking at these cluster representations,
我们希望通过查看这些集群表示，
we'll be able to make better decisions of what to merge or what next to merge.
我们将能够更好地决定合并的内容或合并的内容。
Um, I have a few more slides that go through the Clark and Manning algorithm.
嗯，我还有一些幻灯片通过了Clark和Manning算法。
Um, but I also have just a few minutes left.
嗯，但我还有几分钟的时间。
And so I think I'll skip the details.
所以我想我会跳过细节。
Um, I think the main thing that's interesting here,
嗯，我认为这里有趣的主要事情，
is the idea of clustering based coreference algorithms,
是基于聚类的共参数算法的想法，
and why in principle,
为什么原则上
it should give you extra oomph.
它应该给你额外的魅力。
Um, and that's sort of the main useful thing to get through.
嗯，这是通过的主要有用的东西。
Because what I want to make sure we have covered in
因为我想确保我们已经涵盖了什么
the last few minutes that I've said nothing at all about,
最后几分钟，我什么都没说，
is how do you evaluate coreference resolution and how well does it work?
你是如何评估共指解决方案以及它的工作情况的？
So let me skip ahead to that.
所以让我跳过这个。
Um, so if you look at coreference resolution papers,
嗯，所以如果你看一下共识决议论文，
or something like that,
或类似的东西，
um, there are many metrics that people have used to evaluate coreference,
嗯，有很多人用来评估共指的指标，
and they have a long alphabet soup of names.
他们有一个很长的字母汤。
So there's MUC, and CEAF, and LEA,
所以有MUC，CEAF和LEA，
and B- CUBED, and BLANC and,
和B-CUBED，以及BLANC和，
um, things like that.
嗯，这样的事情。
Um, so effectively part of it is that if you look in the clustering literature,
嗯，如此有效的一部分是，如果你看一下聚类文献，
there are lots of ways that people try and evaluate clustering,
有很多方法可以让人们尝试和评估聚类，
and essentially any of those metrics and some other ones, you can, um,
基本上任何这些指标和其他指标，你可以，嗯，
port over, um, to, um, coreference evaluation.
移动，嗯，嗯，共同评估。
I mean, why it's kind of difficult is the situation you have,
我的意思是，为什么你遇到的情况有点困难，
is that you have a gold standard which picks out certain clusters,
是你有一个黄金标准，挑选出某些集群，
and the system picks out certain clusters,
并且系统挑出某些集群，
and you get some result like this and you have to decide how good it is.
你得到一些像这样的结果，你必须决定它有多好。
So I'm going to show you just quickly one particular algorithm.
所以我将快速向您展示一个特定的算法。
So the B-CUBED algorithm uses
所以B-CUBED算法使用
precision and recall and F-measure like we thought of before.
像我们之前想到的那样精确，召回和F-measure。
So it looks at, uh,
所以它看，呃，
cluster identified by the system.
由系统识别的集群。
And it says, well this cluster is four-fifths,
它说，这个集群是五分之四，
um, gold cluster one,
嗯，黄金集群一，
so the precision is four-fifths.
所以精度是五分之四。
But actually, um, there are six things in gold cluster one.
但实际上，嗯，黄金集群中有六件事情。
So it only has a recall of four-sixth of that cluster.
所以它只召回了该集群的四分之六。
And then it similarly does for the other one,
然后它同样适用于另一个，
the same kind of calculation.
同样的计算。
And then it's going to average across the precisions and recalls,
然后它将在精确度和回忆中平均，
um, and it's going to come up with an overall, um, B-CUBED score.
嗯，它会得出一个整体的，嗯，B-CUBED分数。
Um, in- if you think about this from an algorithm's perspective,
嗯，如果你从算法的角度思考这个问题，
this is actually tricky because I sort of said,
这实际上很棘手，因为我有点说，
um, okay, this cluster is mainly gold cluster one.
嗯，好吧，这个集群主要是黄金集群。
So use that as its reference,
所以用它作为参考，
but that means you have to do a bipartite graph alignment
但这意味着你必须进行二分图对齐
between system clusters, and gold clusters.
系统集群和黄金集群之间。
So hidden in- hidden inside this evaluation,
所以隐藏在这个评估中，
um, system is actually an NP-complete problem.
嗯，系统实际上是NP完全问题。
But in practice you can normally do it heuristically well enough,
但在实践中你通常可以启发式地做到这一点，
that the evaluation method, um,
评价方法，嗯，
runs and works.
跑步和工作。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
And so the kind of thing to notice is that,
所以需要注意的是，
if you under cluster,
如果你在群集下，
you automatically get great precision,
你会自动获得很高的精确度
but you get bad recall.
但你回忆起来很糟糕。
And if you over cluster,
如果你超过集群，
you get- get great recall because everything that should be in the same cluster is,
你得到了很好的回忆，因为应该在同一个集群中的一切都是，
um, but you get terrible precision.
嗯，但你精确度很差。
And so what you want to be doing is balancing those two things.
所以你想要做的就是平衡这两件事。
Okay. Last two minutes,
好的。最后两分钟，
just to give you some idea of performance.
只是为了让你对性能有所了解。
So these are results from the OntoNotes dataset which is about 3,000 documents.
所以这些是OntoNotes数据集的结果，大约有3,000个文档。
Chinese, English, labeled for coreference.
中文，英文，标注为共识。
Um, the scores I'm reporting is actually an average over three metrics.
嗯，我报告的分数实际上是三个指标的平均值。
One of which is the one I just showed you for B-CUBED,
其中一个是我刚给你看的B-CUBED，
um, here are some numbers.
嗯，这里有一些数字。
Um, so Lee et al 2010 was the Stanford system.
嗯，所以Lee等人2010年是斯坦福大学的系统。
So there- there was this shared task evaluation of coreference systems.
所以有共同任务评估共参照系统。
And we believe that Jerry Hobbs, um,
我们相信Jerry Hobbs，嗯，
was still right, and you could do fine with rule-based coreference.
仍然是对的，你可以通过基于规则的共指做得很好。
And so in 2010,
所以在2010年，
we managed to beat all machine learning systems with a rule-based coreference system,
我们设法通过基于规则的共享系统击败所有机器学习系统，
and we were proud of it.
我们为此感到自豪。
Um, and that's its performance right here.
嗯，这就是它的表现。
Um, in subsequent years,
嗯，在随后的几年里，
people did start to do a bit better, um,
人们确实开始做得更好，嗯，
with, um, with, uh, machine learning systems.
和嗯，机器学习系统。
But as you see, not very much,
但正如你所看到的，不是很多，
right for these 2012 systems that this one's somewhat,
这些2012系统的权利，这个有点，
better this one really wasn't better,
更好的这个真的不是更好，
um, this, um, but making a bit of progress.
嗯，这个，嗯，但是取得了一些进展。
Starting in 2015, there started to be neural systems.
从2015年开始，开始出现神经系统。
Um, so Wiseman et al was sort of the first neural system,
嗯，所以Wiseman等人是第一个神经系统，
I vaguely mentioned this Clark &amp; Manning system,
我含糊地提到了这个Clark＆Manning系统，
and the numbers are going up into the mid-sixties.
这些数字正在上升到六十年代中期。
And this is the Kenton Lee system that has the end-to-end neural coreference,
这是具有端到端神经干预的Kenton Lee系统，
and on English is getting about 67.
在英语上大约有67个。
So something you'll notice from this,
所以你会注意到这一点，
is the numbers aren't great.
是数字不是很好。
So coreference is still far from a solved problem.
因此，共识仍远未解决问题。
Um, so if you want to have a bit of fun, um,
嗯，如果你想要有点乐趣，嗯，
you can go out and try coreference systems for yourself.
你可以出去为自己尝试共享系统。
Um, there's a Stanford one on the first link or the one from Hugging Face
嗯，第一个链接上有一个Stanford，或者来自Hugging Face
is a good modern coreference system as well.
是一个很好的现代共同参照系统。
And if you just try these out with some pieces of text,
如果你只是用一些文字来试试这些，
you'll notice they still get lots of things wrong.
你会发现他们仍然有很多错误。
Um, so there's still more work to do,
嗯，还有更多工作要做，
because this is just a harder language understanding task,
因为这只是一个更难理解语言的任务，
[NOISE] which is just kind of like, um,
[NOISE]这有点像，嗯，
Jerry Hobbs and Terry- Terry Winograd earlier observed.
Jerry Hobbs和Terry-Terry Winograd早些时候观察过。
Okay, um, but I'll stop there for now. Thanks a lot.
好的，嗯，但我现在就到此为止。非常感谢。
Um, oh yeah, I should have a reminder, invited speaker next Tuesday.
嗯，是的，我应该提醒，下周二邀请发言人。
Um, so I'll be taking,
嗯，所以我要带，
um, attendance for invited speakers.
嗯，特邀演讲者的出席情况。